because I sure am.
Oh man.
I haven't drunk this much coke since I played Minecraft last, I don't think.
There's just something about the combo.
Fucking ads right now!
Why is it always so badly timed?
Are there ads right now?
That's crazy.
I'm sorry.
I just can't stop hitting the ad button whenever I'm about to say something insightful.
It's automatic.
I'm addicted to hitting the button!
I can't stop!
I get ads all the time.
Then you gotta subscribe!
Just kidding.
I mean, if you don't want ads, then you gotta subscribe.
But yeah, other than that, deal with it.
The ads are there to support my living and my further Minecraft addiction.
Guys, are you excited or what?
I feel like I hit a milestone in Create.
Last time was kind of a banger.
Today I'm gonna be building the house.
I will be exploring new recipes.
I will go explore the nether, maybe.
I will go to the skies in an airplane.
I will go underwater in a scuba diving suit.
And make a submarine.
I will even make a rock.
And make a rocket.
And I will go to the moon.
Maybe not all of that, but some of that for sure.
I have lofty goals.
Let's see if I can achieve them though.
I actually just want to get started.
Guys, I'm sorry.
I was playing off stream.
I couldn't stop.
I played like seven hours or so yesterday.
I'm kidding.
I didn't.
I'm right where we left.
Well, kind of where we left off.
Okay.
Man.
Check this.
Oh my god.
I gotta do this again.
Man.
That is just a fantastic addition.
No more getting stuck.
And making ladders and weird staircases.
Nuh-uh.
Jackie is singing in the background.
Maybe you can hear her.
What was I doing anyway?
I was doing this.
But it was more like an exploratory session of new items.
And stuff.
I think I'm gonna continue.
Oh, no, no, no.
I remember what I was doing.
I was about to make a floor in here.
But I wanted to make the andeside casing floor.
The problem with that is, it's gonna take a long time to do.
So I figured, there's surely a way to automate that.
So that's why I started doing all this.
But I never really got anywhere.
Let me see.
I need to work backwards.
Andeside casing.
We put it on.
Or we mix it on.
Which is so weird.
Uh.
Okay, it's not gonna show me...
What kind of way to automatically make this?
I mean, I have to do it manually, it seems.
For now, at least.
This thing is broken, by the way.
Whoa, I just had a massive lag spike.
By the way, I figured out what the black flickering was on my screen.
Apparently, when you have Apollo installed, it's like a, um, a streaming thing.
So you can stream your computer to other computers.
That fucks with Minecraft!
I figured it out.
That was the reason.
No more black flickering, hopefully.
That's gone.
Um.
Yeah.
Let me see what else I needed to do here.
Basically, I gotta get my basic stuff started, right?
New Dawn Dormitory.
Has not quite finished yet.
But it's looking good, isn't it?
Imagine some windows, and then we put the floor in.
Ooh, yeah.
Very nice.
This we don't need anymore.
I'm gonna make more handlebars.
Hmm, okay.
We're gonna enchant today.
But that means going to the nether.
No, wait, that means...
No.
Potions means going to the nether.
We should make potions as well.
Copper casing.
Have I made this?
Let's make this.
I'm just gonna continue making a couple things before I continue here.
I just wanna see.
Copper casing.
Do I even have copper bars?
Copper bars.
There's no way.
I may have used them all.
That's okay, though.
Dark coal.
Okay, I'm a little lost right now.
So we did this.
Yep.
Okay.
I think I'm just gonna go out there and...
explore a little bit in every direction.
I just wanna see...
what I'm dealing with here.
Let's take a boat.
Boat, boat, boat, boat, boat.
Boat is here.
We also need some sticks.
And some wood.
Yes.
And that's about it.
There's nothing else I should bring, right?
Maybe some dirt for ascension?
Actually, that's good.
Maybe that's too much dirt.
Maybe like...
Ah, that's too much dirt.
Perfect amount.
That way I can pick up a little bit and not have it overflow, you know?
We have the toolbox, of course.
White bed.
Bucket.
Spyglass.
What do I have on five normally?
Oh, yeah!
Torches, of course.
But that means coal, which I don't have.
Damn!
We gotta go find some coal.
Yeah, definitely.
That's one thing.
And...
Oh, maybe I should make a book, actually.
Note down what I need to find.
I was gonna make a book anyway.
Let me see here.
Book.
And quill.
Oh, we need feathers.
Ink sacks.
I have one ink sack, but I have no feathers.
Let's go find a chicken.
Surely that can't be hard.
Oh, also today we're gonna get the basics done, like, uh, getting animals.
But for that I need a lead, and I forgot how to make a lead.
I can probably find it in the book.
See sheep over there?
Where are the chickens at?
Really?
Oh, that's ugly.
This was my, uh, flow testing.
There.
Fixed.
I wanna keep this area pristine, you know?
I don't wanna take down the trees or anything.
It's beautiful here.
Oh, there's an egg.
That means there's chickens.
Oh, yeah.
Ah, let me see.
Yeah, kill him.
No feather?
There we go.
I think I just needed one feather.
I'm happy.
And we can make a cake now.
Probably one of the most useless items in Minecraft.
You can't even eat them properly.
It's a mess.
Book and quill.
Ink sack.
One.
Wait, why can't I see it?
What am I missing?
Oh, book.
Of course.
There we go.
We got it.
Ah, nice.
Okay.
What we need.
We need coal.
How we doing on andesite?
Uh, that would be here.
Andesite.
52.
We could do with a bit more andesite.
Andesite.
And what else do I need?
What do I absolutely need?
We have a lot of wood.
Actually, we don't have that much oak.
Like logs, you know?
Which we need to make the encasing or whatever.
of the metal.
Yeah, okay.
I'll take the crank.
I'm gonna crank a bit.
Bring the saw and the crank.
Ultimate combo.
And other than that, what else do I need?
For the house.
We have the floor.
Hmm.
I think I'm good there.
Yeah, I definitely need more logs because I want to strip them and also use the stripped wood.
That's one of the things.
Oh!
I remember what I was doing last time.
I was making the breathing apparatus.
And I got distracted.
Copper diving helmet.
And boots.
And I need to figure out how to make that tank.
Shit.
So we got glass and we got...
Yeah, how did that not unlock with glass?
So I really gotta solve that one first.
I need to crank the tank so we can dive deep and get the materials we need.
Maybe I'll make another shield, actually.
There we go.
Well, this one is useless right now, actually.
Let's just leave that for now.
We also have cardboard we could use things or do things with.
Maybe that was the key.
Cardboard.
Let's make a cardboard sword.
Let me see what that feels like.
We got boots.
What is the point of this?
Oh, the stealth stuff.
Sneak to activate an inconspicuous disguise.
Hmm.
I don't think I have enough to actually make a full set.
I can make a block of cardboard.
I don't know what I'll need that for but now I have it.
Oh, I already made one.
Damn.
Shit.
Waste of cardboard.
Not bad.
Alright, what else?
Have we made a trapdoor yet?
We have now.
Ladder?
That's construction.
Thrapdoor.
The idea is to make as much as possible to see what we can unlock with it.
Oh, we probably...
Oh, we probably need this, actually.
Can I somehow unsheet these back into ingots?
Is that a thing?
Wait.
No, I don't think so.
Alright, we definitely gotta go find some copper.
Let's do that real quick.
And we don't need these chickens with us.
We can cook them.
Come in there.
Give me that.
In.
Yeah, we definitely need coal.
And some kind of, uh...
Perhaps even better power source.
It's not good enough.
Oh!
I think we should just go down into the cave again.
Honestly.
Or find the new cave.
Let's find the new cave.
Can't wait to try this cardboard sword.
Let's use it on somebody.
It's like punishing someone for bad behavior, you know?
Hit them across the fingers.
Hey!
Ah-ha!
Oh, wait a second!
This is a non-lethal weapon.
You can use this to relocate animals.
Oh, that is actually massive!
This is incredibly useful!
I don't need a lead!
What's up, dude?
You're coming back with me!
Ah!
Oh, shit!
I fell in the water.
Hey, cow!
Come here!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Get up!
Come on!
Boing!
No, no, no!
No!
Come on!
Get out of here!
You stupid cow!
Come on!
Oh, there we go.
We got him.
Just gonna spam the button.
You're coming back with me.
Oh.
Maybe there's a way to ride these cows.
Forward, noble steed.
You know?
Oh, we just got something new.
We can mill that.
Make die, I guess.
We gotta make a little enclosure.
Oh, shit.
Uh, where do I put you?
Oh, we actually need some...
Oh, shit.
Uh...
Stand by, stand by.
Stand by.
Uh, use this.
Uh, fence?
48.
Hey, buddy.
Uh, where should I put you?
Come on.
This way.
Maybe I'll do it right over here-ish.
Hmm.
Get rid of this tree.
No, you're coming back here.
Come here.
Yep, yep, yep.
I need to wait inside as well.
Okay, there we go.
There we go.
You cannot leave.
You need to stay here.
I will take care of you.
Oh, I have a shovel.
Ha!
For some reason, I thought I didn't have a shovel.
We also need a gate, of course.
That's obvious.
There we go, buddy.
I'm gonna get a friend for you.
What if I mingle the cows and the sheep?
The dogs and the cats.
Everyone.
Goes in the same enclosure.
I'm pretty sure I saw another cow.
There you are.
Come here!
I wonder if I can crit him with it.
Go in faster.
No?
Okay.
Boing.
Dude, this is actually amazing.
This may even be better than the lead.
I'm not even kidding.
If you get proficient at this, animal spanking is now a new thing.
To get them where you want them to go.
Come here.
This way.
Because the lead keeps falling off, right?
This one doesn't.
And the best part?
We can just immediately put him inside.
By spanking him.
Get in!
Ah!
Ooh!
Okay, you can't go in.
That's fine.
Get in!
Boom!
Now Keith.
Okay.
So, I actually forgot what cows eat.
I think it's seeds.
I have seeds.
I have a lot.
What's up, guys?
Look what I got for you.
No, it's not seeds.
Hmm.
Oh, I know!
I know what it is!
It's fucking hay, isn't it?
Oh, I mean wheat.
Same thing, I guess?
Yeah!
Make baby!
Beautiful!
The parrots and the bats.
And the dogs and the cats.
All right.
Let me see here.
Do-do-do-do-do.
The parrots and the bats.
Plant a seed and watch it grow.
You could argue that what I just did was also planting a seed and watch it grow.
With this exact icon.
You know?
I planted a seed in their mouth.
And now it will grow out to become a little baby.
Also, I gotta read these achievements more.
Assemble a windmill of maximum strength.
Oh, I haven't even done that!
I thought for sure we were at max strength by now.
Okay, so we need more wool.
We gotta kill sheep.
No, we gotta...
Cat sheep!
Make them breed and then kill them.
And I've got my cardboard spanker ready.
For anyone who misbehaves in here.
Wait, why is that tree growing on another tree?
Never mind, it's a tall tree.
It looked like this tree was growing on top of that tree.
Weird.
Optical illusions.
Also, these birch trees are unusually tall.
I've never seen them like this.
Whoa.
Yo!
Oh my god!
This is amazing!
We are gonna make a bridge across here!
This is such a cool place, man!
I love this place I'm in!
It's beautiful!
Here we go, sheep!
Can I grab two at a time here?
If I'm smart.
Where's the other sheep?
Oh, there's multiple.
Great.
So you come this way.
There we go.
And now...
Bam-bam.
Okay, maybe when you have two sheep, it's easier with the lead.
But, you know.
Come on.
No, ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah.
Eee!
We just had to do that, didn't you?
No, not the water!
Okay, you're dead to me.
You come with me.
Let's not go that way, actually.
Let's just circumvent that hole.
That way.
Now we're cooking.
Check this out.
I need to make another enclosure.
Uh, here and there.
There, there.
Boing, boing.
I'm so happy I made this sword!
This is such a nice addition.
I wonder if I can do this on, uh, villagers.
That would be my dream.
Okay, we're almost there.
We're almost there.
There we go.
Look at this!
You know what?
I'm actually gonna put you in the same enclosure.
We are, uh, you know, lacking space right now.
Temporary measures.
Come here, come here.
And in you go!
Oh, shit.
No, no, no, no, no, no!
No, no!
In!
I said, in!
No, you are not leaving.
You are...
Please don't walk away from me.
Oh, my...
GOOOOOOODD!
I hate this.
Spanking is bad.
Oh, you know what?
We need a fucking gate!
Come on!
Quick!
In!
Lock it!
Now the sheep.
This is the way.
Yep.
Oh, this is beautiful, beautiful.
In!
Bo-ha-ha-ha!
I got you!
I got you now.
Hey, you like wheat?
Hey, go make baby.
Let me see the baby.
There we go, beautiful.
Wonderful!
Mission successful.
While we're at it, we should get some chickens.
While the getting is good, you know?
Just a couple.
It's all you need.
Wait, you know what?
Hold on.
Can I actually make a lead?
Oh!
It sounded like, like, oh, in the distance, but it's actually just a windmill.
What was I just saying?
I just forgot.
I was doing...
Oh yeah, a lead!
No, I don't know how to make it.
Shit.
I think it's something to do with leather.
You put leathers together and, you know, a lead comes out.
Something like that.
Now...
Oh!
Shit!
Hey!
There we go.
Fine.
The pristine environment.
It's been soiled.
There.
Nobody knows.
We unlock new things as well.
Okay, chickens.
Oh, hello there.
Don't not explode.
I would really hate that.
Here we go.
One chicken found.
We got another one?
We got another one.
Let's get it.
Oh, you're fli- Ah!
That's funny!
You like flying when I do this.
There we go.
We're not gonna go over any chasms.
Beautiful.
Oh, you're pooping out a little thing as we go.
I love it.
Keep pooping.
Boink, boink.
Uh, here.
Wait, maybe we can actually make these guys fly into the enclosure.
Because they're flying, right?
And I don't need to open it for them.
Uh-oh.
This way.
That way.
Do not fall in the hole.
I will be very angry.
Let's see it.
Moment of truth.
Uh...
Come on.
And?
Oh, no.
No!
You know what?
Oh, my God!
It's a shit.
Dude, I hate this thing!
I can't wait to get a lead!
It's infuriating.
Lock him in!
It ain't going nowhere, buddy!
This is temporary enclosure.
Same as you.
I don't give a shit anymore.
Oh, God.
Uh, fence?
Go.
Where do you go?
Check in!
Seriously, where did you go?
Well, he's in the back rooms now.
There's no way he's on Earth anymore.
He just disappeared off the face of the Earth.
Great.
I turned my back for five seconds!
How is this possible?
What the fuck just happened?
Where the hell is he?
This is insane!
There you are!
It's just like, you know, putting your keys down and then they just disappear.
Hey, you know what?
Yeah!
Okay, we can definitely get you in now.
One of them is in.
Clean this up.
Come on.
Oh, we gotta get you upstairs like this.
There we go.
And now?
Boing!
Oh.
No!
Shit!
Boing!
In!
He almost escaped!
Oh, man.
We did it.
That was more painful than it needed to be.
That was just unnecessarily horrible.
Wow.
I'm glad that's over with.
Let's go harvest.
Dude, this is my new favorite harvester.
Definitely gotta fix that one.
Here.
Good.
All this crappin'.
Strip the birch lock.
Use the X.
Dude, can I crank the chicken somehow?
Imagine what happens then if I can use a mechanical saw on them.
Kind of want to try, you know?
Morbid curiosity.
Call it that.
Like, did they actually design it that way?
Or not?
I think we're ready here.
Are we good in here?
That's good.
Good to hear.
All right.
Let's go.
Bed we got.
We got a bed.
We got this.
We are good.
I really need to make another exploration checklist at some point.
At some point, that exploration checklist is going to include, you know, diving, helmet, and all that stuff.
It's going to become the norm.
Same as the jukebox.
Or no, the toolbox.
It's going to become part of the norm.
All right.
Let's go find some copper.
That was the whole plan, right?
I see some copper right there.
Let's make a primitive bridge for primitive people.
Oh, I see a little thing down there.
Oh, look.
I've been down there before.
I see torches.
I was walking there.
That's so funny.
I haven't been in here, though.
Why is there a little pumpkin here?
All right.
Well, I have a pumpkin, though.
Wonderful.
Look at this.
Oh, I need coal.
Oh, shit.
We need coal.
Otherwise, I can't see shit.
I see some coal already.
We need this immediately.
There we go.
That's a good start.
Get back.
Nice.
Also, I brought the hole for no reason.
Maybe there's a way to produce coal, you know?
I don't want to carry this around, actually.
Just fill up the hole.
Stupid bats.
Definitely need to make more torches.
54.
That's a great amount.
Oh, and copper.
Copper is what we needed.
Let's grab that.
That's why I came here.
I will light this entire place.
Down the line.
It will all be lit.
Also, how the hell do I even get a...
Like, an easy supply of arrows?
I seem to have forgotten how to do that in an easy way, you know?
It seems like such a big challenge to start collecting arrows and getting a bow.
We have andesite here.
Coal, we have everything we need here.
I wonder if I can make a gondola.
I'm imagining one of those they have in Switzerland or whatever.
You know, you go on it and...
It's like a little, um, cab.
And it's on, you know, lines or whatever.
And you go up and down.
Like a ski lift.
Thing.
A little child down there?
No, that's a grown-ass zombie.
Oh!
We actually need to focus on enchanting.
Because, imagine we get looting, right?
That's like the tipping point.
That's when it starts to become really valuable to go out here and collect shit.
It's actually so painful not having that.
I'm gonna light this as well.
Woo!
Hello!
Ow!
Copper?
More copper.
More lampus bread.
Uh, give me this.
To be fair, though, you get a lot of copper really fast.
even without the enchantment.
Uh, that's risky.
Never stand on the block that you're mining.
Number one rule of Minecraft.
Not sure how we're doing on sync, but I can take a couple zincs.
I'm actually gonna make a crafting table.
I can't.
Oh, you know what we could do?
Trial chamber.
That's how you get a lot of copper fast.
It's actually very inefficient compared to that.
We should find one.
It's usually quite deep.
Uh, wait.
Yeah, okay.
It's fine.
So I've been down there.
This is a crazy cave, man.
Oh, by the way, I haven't died a single time ever since I said I wouldn't die.
Have you noticed?
In this world.
The first one doesn't count, remember?
That was the unfair one.
The one nobody could have foreseen.
Okay.
I think I got what I came for.
Let's go back and see what we can make with this copper.
And then I think it's time we go to the nether.
Because I definitely want to see what kind of recipes we can get from, you know, nether materials.
You know what?
Actually, yeah.
Let's fight it out.
I need experience.
Because I'm going to the nether and I'm going to enchant shit.
It's going to be good.
I'll leave you living.
Oh, man.
It feels so homey already.
Sleep.
Cheers.
I barely touched my drink.
Man, I get tears in my eyes every time I drink that because it's so beautiful.
You ever get that feeling?
So good.
Okay, let's start blasting.
Oh, I can also make charcoal, I guess.
That's also a good idea.
Because I have so much wood, right?
Why wouldn't I?
Some chickens.
So, if we are going to the nether, we're going to need obsidian.
Which means we're going to need a bucket of water, which we have, pretty much.
We've got to find some lava.
Actually, I may actually have lava.
Can I collect lava?
I guess not.
Dude, I'm excited about the item vault.
There are so many things I want to try today.
But it's good that we have some basic stuff down like this, you know?
Let's feed them again.
Everyone gets fed.
Hey, chickens!
Wait, chickens want chicken feed.
I like chicken feed.
Give me this one.
Hey!
Come here!
Look what I got for you.
That's for you.
This one has your name on it.
There you go.
And I think I saw someone else.
You want one?
There you go.
You got one now.
Look at how they're thriving.
We will, of course, make a bigger enclosure so they can really have a nice time.
And inside that enclosure, we're going to have trees.
We're going to have a little pond for them to play in.
You know, they can flap their little wings in the water and go plop, plop, plop, plop, plop.
It's going to be so good.
I have grand divisions for this.
Bones.
Wait!
We can do something with bones.
Bone.
We're definitely doing that.
Hold on.
Wait a second.
Can I make that?
Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh, duh, duh.
Have I made it before?
Wait a second.
Um, mill.
Anticide casing.
Anticide cockwheel.
I have that.
That is no problem.
Cockwheel and I think I saw a diorite.
Wait, I already have one.
It's fate.
Mill.
Mill me.
Okay, so this one requires one of these, right?
Look at that, baby.
We can even just plop things in immediately.
Where's my bones?
Watch this.
Oh, it's crushing it up good.
Embrace the grind.
Wait, which one is that?
Oh, this one.
Super glue some blocks into a group.
I am like 90% sure that I need honey or something for that.
Or maybe the green gloop, you know?
Okay.
Come on, baby!
Are we done?
Not yet.
You also got some white dye out of that.
That's cool.
Oh, wait a minute.
Are we done here?
Oh, this is what I wanted to do as well.
I almost forgot.
We're not done cooking here.
Put this in here for now.
Raw iron.
Rotten flesh.
And pumpkin.
Let's keep a pumpkin somewhere here.
Somewhere nice.
Next to the farm.
Right there.
That's beautiful.
I'm even gonna fill this up because this was not something we wanted to have happen.
This is more pretty.
And you know what?
We don't need this anymore.
Because we have this.
Look at me cleaning shit up.
Isn't that beautiful?
Boing, boing, boing.
Boing.
I like to boing my...
Oh wait, no, I don't want to say that sentence.
You know what I mean!
Ha ha ha ha!
Shit.
Wait, I already had one!
I had a millstone!
Look!
Fuck!
Wait a second.
I wonder...
Can I or can I not combine them?
Oh!
Look how pretty that is!
36...
Wait, am I actually getting more bone meal out of this?
Than usual?
Hold on.
One bone becomes three bone meal.
But...
If I do it here...
Uh...
Bone meal...
25% chance for three extra it seems.
Or we get white dye.
So I guess it is better.
Definitely.
Right.
Okay.
We can pack it together into a bone block.
Love packing!
I'm actually doing some packing right now.
Oh, you know what?
We should make one of those bells.
No!
Don't get distracted, fucker!
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna focus on one thing at a time.
We were gonna make something out of these copper ingots.
Copper.
Block of copper.
Yeah!
Back tank!
I saw it!
Let's fucking go, dude.
Shaft and alloys.
I got it.
Here we go.
Are you ready to crank it?
Because I'm gonna crank the shit out of this.
Let me see how this works again.
Right.
Back here.
So...
That's like...
Wait.
Can I use this for that?
There's no way, right?
Oh, it doesn't reach.
Okay.
Maybe over here?
Wait, what?
Maybe we need a big wheel?
Wait, I forgot how this worked.
Wait a second.
Put it down, and then...
Give me a wheel.
Why is it not...
I mean, these are the wheels.
It's a big wheel.
Big wheel.
I don't have that?
Make it.
I guess we have to do this first, and then...
Bro, I don't understand what's happening right now.
Hold
on.
Can I...
I mean, yeah.
Wait, how the hell did I do this last time?
Why am I blanking on this so hard?
Let's try and crank that shit.
Did I just do this?
What did I do?
Oh!
It's the top!
Okay.
Right.
That explains so much.
I was fooled by the visual!
The wheels!
Freaking wheels, man.
Alright, so in that case...
Easy.
Uh, that means...
Wait, can I...
Can I...
...piggyback one of these?
If I'm smart.
Give me that one.
And probably...
Can I turn it upside down, maybe?
No.
Can't crank it upside down.
I guess I can put it down below.
I won't do this in a...
Oh!
We also have a wheel here!
Hello!
Look at that!
I mean, it's not elegant, but you know.
It's a temporary measure.
It's okay.
Shaft time.
And then...
You.
It's cranking!
Yep!
Fill it up.
And then we're gonna get ready with the...
Headpiece.
There we go.
And the diving boots.
Oh, man.
Oh, boy.
This is gonna be great.
This is gonna be a really fun...
Expedition.
What else did I unlock with that?
I feel like that was more.
White postbox!
Huh?
Okay.
Let's make this.
Thanks.
Steam engine.
I am very curious about that.
Basin.
We should make a button.
Nah.
We only make the button when we need it.
And right now, we don't need it, technically.
The button comes later.
Get rid of this.
I'm just cleaning up the inventory a little bit here.
Actually, I can take this and start cooking that.
Look at that experience we're getting.
It's glorious.
I should do this one first.
I really should put a little, uh...
Hopper on that, actually.
Hopper...
Uh...
Not right now.
Later.
Let's go to bed.
I'm getting a little overwhelmed already.
I need to just...
Have a focused...
Plan.
There we go.
Put it in.
Book and quill.
This one always comes with me.
The millstone is in here.
We keep the crank.
The shield we keep as well.
The saw...
This is like the, uh...
The golden trio, you know?
We always need these three.
Water bucket.
We don't need the hoe.
Don't need these either.
Not right now, at least.
The boat is essential.
There we go.
I think we're good here.
Look how clean that is.
Definitely want to keep the...
Keep the cardboard sword.
Bonk!
A mostly harmless, yet powerful weapon of choice.
It is an incredible item.
Okay.
I think that was about it.
Nothing else I wanted to do before I leave?
Torsion spring?
What?
Wait, let me see the achievements here.
Strong breeze.
Oh yeah, I needed to kill sheep.
Oh, we have those back there.
We could actually kill a couple.
No, keep feeding them, and then we kill them later.
Hmm.
Yo, we need to find a way to automatically kill them.
There's gotta be...
There's gotta be a way.
I wonder...
Hold on a minute.
You bastard.
Oh, wait.
They can't...
No.
Oh no, fuck!
Get out of the way!
You know, okay.
That means you die.
Congratulations, you escaped.
Now you die.
This is the prize.
Let that be a lesson to all of you.
If you try to escape, you will be killed.
Bastards.
We got some wool again.
Only one right now.
That ain't good.
I do gotta bring some wood.
32.
Okay.
Let me see.
Oh!
Nether!
Right!
So, uh...
Find lava.
Let me actually write that down.
Nether.
We don't need coal anymore.
Still do need andesite.
Nether and...
Lava.
Uh, before we do that, we need lava.
And then we need to fill this up.
We already did.
Great.
Oh, maybe a bit more food.
Just for safety.
Put the leather in there.
Dude, let's go diving!
Is this thing done?
It's only halfway.
Damn!
Dude, can we make this go a little...
Hold on.
We're gonna cheat physics a little bit here.
Just...
Quickly.
We're just gonna do a little bit of that.
There's some temporary shit I'm making here, okay?
Not supposed to be pretty.
Oh, wait.
No, no, no.
Here.
One more, maybe?
To go a little crazy?
Shit.
That's too fast, I think.
Yeah.
Let's just leave it at that.
Much better!
Look at that!
Look how fast that's filling up.
I wish I could see some kind of, uh...
Like, progress bar on that while it's doing it.
Hmm.
But it's gonna be fast.
Okay, put these back.
Mechanical saw.
Uh, we gotta make some more pulp as well.
Why?
Because I wanna try and be stealthy.
So while I'm waiting, let's just do that.
Can I just throw in some random crap?
What if I throw in seats?
What happens then?
Wait a minute.
Seat.
Okay, there's nothing there.
Let me just see.
Is it gonna start mixing?
Nope.
That means it's not working.
Okay.
It was worth a try, though.
Let me see.
Man.
That takes a while, too!
Fill up, huh?
You know what?
This is fine.
I'm happy.
I probably don't need more than this, anyway.
And worst case, we can always crank it manually.
Okay, here we go.
Boom.
There.
Oh, yeah.
And then we put on the thing, of course.
Dude, look at that!
You ready?
Let's do it.
Saw is here.
Dirt is here.
Oh, we don't need these.
Put those back.
Put the shield on.
Time for an expedition.
Yep.
We're gonna write down what we need to do as we go along.
Let's just head north.
This was the original plan, anyway.
Let me see here.
Welcome to create.
Let me see what else I need to focus on.
Yeah, we gotta kill sheep.
Oh, that's right.
Write it down.
Lava.
Right.
We gotta look for lava.
Oh, I see fire!
Look!
I think there's lava over there.
Why else would there be fire?
Huh?
Fucking detective over here.
Unbelievable.
I'm actually such a professional.
That was some Class 8 deduction right there.
Maybe we'll put a stop to that fire.
We cannot get lost either.
We gotta be careful.
What's going on here, guys?
I see crimes.
I see lava!
Thank you.
Would you look at...
Oh, this is a mess, isn't it?
Let's put a stop to that.
Yeah!
It's gonna take a million years, though.
To gather this obsidian.
Wonderful.
Let's put a stop to this up here as well.
It hit none of the fires?
How is that even fucking possible?
Alright, whatever.
The forest shall burn down.
It's okay.
I can't even see how fast this is.
Oh, there we go.
Ooh, nice.
Ice Bucket Challenge.
I don't know why it's called that.
Oh, I get it.
Because bucket of water.
Wait a minute.
Is this game...
I feel like this game is older than that meme.
The Ice Bucket Challenge?
Right?
Minecraft, like that...
Damn, I'm feeling old now.
I feel really old.
Also, I forgot how many I needed.
I think nine.
Wait, let me see.
One, two...
I'll figure it out.
Gimme.
Oh!
We need to get some gold as well.
By the way.
Otherwise, we're gonna have a bad time in the nether.
But maybe I invite bad times.
You know?
Maybe I'm not afraid anymore.
Wearing gold is...
You know...
The noob way.
Okay, let me actually think.
One, two...
That's four...
Six...
Seven...
No, it's one higher.
If I'm not mistaken, this is the...
Yep, this is it for sure.
Why do I have a memory of nine?
I'm imagining things.
It's ten.
And I have nine.
One more.
Yep, okay.
I'm happy with that.
Oh, this is still burning.
You know what?
Let's just stop this.
We can't have this happen.
Oh, you know what?
Check this out.
This is how you stop a forest fire.
Sick!
We're gonna do it over here, too.
Oh, that is beautiful.
We should go to sleep.
Before the monsters come.
Taking these two.
Oh, man.
The fire's spreading everywhere.
We actually can't have that.
Oh, Christ.
Did I leave the...
Oh, no.
I left my crank.
Oh, man.
Oh, it's spreading so much!
Wait, how do you actually stop this?
Did...
There's actually no way to stop this!
What the fuck?
Oh, my God!
Here comes the gang all of a sudden.
Quick!
Crank it!
Again, again.
Come on.
Good.
Oh, this one's burning.
But it's good.
It's very early.
It's early.
Come on.
Good.
You have a couple burning...
Okay, this one stopped.
Nice!
We actually fucking stopped it!
Now we get rid of these.
Yeah!
We saved the forest!
Unbelievable.
And you know what?
It's a win-win because we also got a bunch of wood out of it.
Which I wanted to get.
I needed that anyway.
So, great!
Just gonna remove some crimes here.
Oh, these are natural crimes, you know?
And you know what?
I need all these saplings too, to make pulp.
So I can make more cardboard.
Move me some cardboard.
So I wonder how this is gonna work.
It's connected to the...
To the ground there.
So...
Let's see.
Okay, still works.
Lovely.
This one is intact.
This is a sad tree.
We gotta take it out of its misery.
And that is all she wrote, I think.
Why is there sand here?
It's a very weird place.
There's also sand over there.
Just random pockets of sand.
Okay!
Good.
Check this out.
Whoa!
Let's see.
36, baby!
What the fuck?
That's crazy.
We're just gonna put a bunch of shit in here.
Wow.
Wowie.
Maybe some...
Rotten flesh, I guess?
Gunpowder?
We're gonna get more of that, for sure.
Don't need to seize right now.
Here, that's for you.
Eat.
Dude, this toolbox is insane.
Okay, let's try the water.
Ten minutes of breathing?
Not bad.
Hey, this is actually...
Oh, we can't sprint, though.
That's a bummer, but that's fine.
A good trade-off, though.
Hell yeah.
Now, you may say, why is this such a big deal?
It is because...
Imagine exploring a cave that you normally couldn't, because it was, you know, overflowing with water.
Now, though, if I see a cave, I can just jump down.
Also, we gotta be careful not to get lost.
Oh, wait a second.
How do we deal with darkness in the water?
We need a headlamp or something.
Hmm.
Maybe there's a way to make a headlamp or a little, uh...
Like, underwater flashlight.
Oh, I guess we can use, um...
Night vision.
Right?
And I do remember we need carrots for that one.
Let's go.
Okay, so we got...
Hold on.
Let me write this down.
Nether.
I should say...
Obsidian.
Check.
Uh, lava.
Oh, wait!
Lava!
Oh, I destroyed all the lava!
Okay, the next lava we see we're gonna grab with the bucket.
Other than that, uh...
Andesite.
Yeah, I'm gonna collect that at some point.
It's fine.
Dude, this place reminds me of, uh...
Of an area in...
In my last world.
Something about this feels familiar.
We're just going north.
We cannot get lost.
In fact, I have a torch on the other side over there.
Let me see if I can see it from here.
Why can't I see that?
It should be over there somewhere.
I'm just gonna put a torch in between...
These two trees.
This is very recognizable.
Right there.
Look at this.
I will never get lost with this.
Let's go.
I'm going to fight crimes.
For example, that one is a little crimey.
And we're gonna checklist the whole list of checks.
That made no sense.
But you know what I mean.
That's a weird acacia tree just sitting there.
I will take care of this immediately.
No longer will I just stand by and observe.
I will act.
When I see crimes.
Can I actually get through here?
Guess not.
This looks a bit weird.
Also, I have to remember, I can go anywhere.
I can just go on the floor of the ocean if I wanted to.
Yo, we can...
Hold on.
We can, like, go out in the middle and then...
You know how divers fall backwards into the water like that?
That's what we're gonna do.
Oh my god.
Stop that.
Oh, look at that one!
Hey!
Let's check it out!
Mushroom time!
Hey!
There's probably some cool recipes with that, right?
There's gotta be.
Also, I'm not getting lost.
I know where I am.
Oh, look at it over there!
Oh, we should get some of that too!
We should get all kinds of stuff.
In fact, I really should just be picking up everything, you know?
For potential recipes.
Oh, Danish cows!
Love to see it.
Very overpriced these days.
God damn minced meat.
What's up, fools?
You just dropped that.
That's right.
Let me try this, though.
How do I just...
There we go.
We got milk!
But do I want...
Can I...
No.
What am I doing here, anyway?
Oh, let me get this.
Oh, it's just dirt.
What the...
Huh?
Do we have the little fishes?
Why is this being destroyed?
Why can't I take this?
Oh, wait.
Little mushrooms are coming out.
I see.
Oh, no.
Wait.
I see what...
I know what's happening.
Fuckin' hell.
I don't want to be here, then.
Let's go this way.
No, thanks.
20 brown mushrooms.
Let's get some of this.
I don't know what else I should be bringing.
I don't see anything else that is special here.
Kind of don't want to kill them all.
I'll just leave them be.
For now.
Yeah.
Could be cool to have, like, a little fortress here at some point.
With a lighthouse!
Huh?
Maybe this is the place for the lighthouse.
Gonna kill you...
Oh, shit.
No!
I'm...
How do I...
Get up!
How do I actually go up, then?
Wait.
What?
Fuck.
Do I have to take it off?
Okay.
I guess you have to take it off.
I will murder you now.
You shall be mine.
Sorry.
I really am so...
Oh.
Fish!
Good shit.
I just wanted to check.
You know?
You never know what's gonna happen.
Why do my character just do that?
I don't like that.
Look!
Hmm.
Oh, what a beautiful sunset.
Wait.
So that means west?
South.
Where do I go?
A lot of water here.
I think I should just go caving, actually.
Oh.
Nah!
Don't explore that.
No thanks.
Yeah, they're already doing the weird thing again.
Please don't make it happen.
In front of my face.
Don't do it!
Eee!
Okay.
Dude, are you following me?
Why are they still doing that?
Bastards.
Okay.
Let me see the book again.
Wool.
We actually really need that.
For the achievement.
Lava.
Let's find some.
Maybe there's some up here.
I also gotta go to bed.
Actually put on these then.
I guess I don't need to wear this helmet all the time.
It's more safe this way.
The weirdest place of all.
To sleep.
But it's okay.
Let's explore this place.
We could actually go to the nether right now.
Dude, I like this area.
I am so happy about my base.
It's the perfect place for it.
We have all these cool landmarks and islands and stuff.
This is my jam right here, guys.
This is the best.
Love this type of biome.
What's that?
Dark oak?
Or is it spruce?
Because I could do with some spruce, actually.
That looks like spruce to me.
Did I actually get some spruce already?
No, that was dark oak.
But this is definitely spruce.
Spin that shit.
Show me the goods.
It's actually not even spruce.
What the hell?
It totally looked like it.
Oh,
wait, wait, wait.
That's the limit.
Look!
256.
Okay, it's not infinite.
Good to know.
All right.
So there is a limit to the fantasy.
Good to know.
Hey.
Oh, wow, you're fast.
I actually kind of need your armor.
Mind if I take that?
Hey, hey!
I'm ready for the nether.
Golden leggings.
I'm trying to think what else I should be collecting here.
I need, like, varied new blocks, you know?
Mushroom.
You know what?
Kill some chickens when I see them, because I need feathers.
Maybe I'll take these as well.
Also, I know where I am, by the way.
I'm not lost.
I know exactly where I am.
I wonder if this also changes something about maps.
Maybe there's a whole mapping thingy going on.
I thought that was lava for a second.
Sorry, guys.
You need to die.
Daddy needs your feathers.
Ah, wait a minute.
We can just get lava in the nether, obviously.
That is, like, the obvious place to get it.
Oh, we're back here.
It's kind of beautiful.
I wonder if there's more lava down below here.
Would you look at that?
Yoink!
We got it!
Why didn't I think about that?
That is so obvious in hindsight.
Okay, that marks that.
X on that.
Andeside.
Oops.
We can get some andeside, I guess.
Just a bit.
A couple stacks, maybe.
Also good to just explore areas around my home.
You know?
Reveal the territory.
See what's out there.
Oh!
Wool!
That's another thing.
I need to kill all sheep.
Cannot forget that.
I kind of need everything.
You know what?
I don't need these.
Because I have the helmet.
Ah, but I do need this.
Because I can disenchanted.
No, I can't.
Because it's not enchanted.
Wait.
I wonder if I can make...
String, huh?
Wait, what?
Oh!
Bound block of cardboard.
Interesting.
Okay.
White seeds.
Dude.
I can easily get String.
Imagine...
I need an Orphan Crusher, but for spiders.
And I imagine there's got to be an easier way of doing that.
Now that we have this mod.
Right?
An automatic way of killing them.
That has to be possible.
Maybe with the saw, or something similar.
If we can do that, we pretty much have infinite wool.
If you have infinite strings, you have infinite wool.
And vice versa.
But I guess I can also just kill sheep in that case.
Why even go trouble of killing spiders if it didn't get strings if it didn't get wool?
Hmm.
Yeah.
Now that I think about it.
I just killed sheep.
Wow.
Let's go up here and see what's going on.
I want a nice view.
Speaking of view...
What is my thing set at?
I need to crank that shit, dude!
It wasn't even at the highest!
Yeah!
There we go.
Better.
Crank it up.
Hello.
Oh, yeah.
I am a menace to wildlife.
I shall murder everyone.
Oh, I thought this was like a mountain.
Where I could get a nice view.
But I probably can't up here.
You gotta scope the area.
Wait, what's going on here?
Look at this!
That is kind of cool.
Imagine like...
Dude, imagine a base down here.
And we have tunnels going through the mountain.
Coming from all sides.
Going in.
Because we have to connect everything.
It needs to happen.
This is great.
What a spot, man.
This place gets better and better.
As time goes on.
Just to get some recipes, of course.
Ooh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold the phone.
Bees.
That means there's a bee house.
Somewhere.
And if there's a bee house, we can apply fire to it, right?
Campfire.
Oh, wait, how do I make that?
Is it via a crafting table?
Probably is.
What's the difference?
Of course, dirt.
No thanks.
I need to...
get some wood.
Like a quick crafting table.
Yep.
Dude, my inventory is way too full!
Okay, I don't need these flowers right now, actually.
I also don't need that right now.
Shit!
What did I just throw?
Oh, eggs.
That's fine.
Bone I keep, of course.
Don't need this, either.
Oh, shit!
It needs coal!
Wait, I have it, I think.
Oh.
No, I don't!
Oh, my God.
This is turning into a disaster.
Well, at least we know where the bees are.
I'll come back for the bees.
They will be mine.
Because I have a feeling I can make glue with it.
You know?
With the honey.
What's up, buddy?
Dude, I don't know what's happening.
I feel like I just know where I am at all times.
Like, I don't...
I cannot get lost anymore.
I know my base is there.
It's right over there.
Oh, another bee home.
Let's see.
My house is right...
There.
Boom!
What'd I say?
Oh, we got lava over there, too.
Good to know.
What else can we see from here?
Ooh, man.
You know, there's a massive cave network down below here.
And it's, like, super connected, too.
Want to see something cool?
Yeah!
You may think that was risky, but it wasn't.
Because it was an easy jump.
There's no way you could have missed that.
Hey, you want to see something cool?
Holy shit, that's deep.
Whoa!
That is deep.
Damn, dude.
Oh, nice!
Another bee house.
That means...
Oh, okay, okay.
Let's just do that, then.
Let me see this achievement again, because this explains it.
Somewhere.
Husbandry.
Use a campfire to collect honey from a beehive using a glass bottle without aggravating the bees.
Because campfires make them docile.
I learned that recently, actually.
I forgot where.
Oh, in Sims, I think, actually.
That's where I learned that.
Of all places.
What's up, dude?
Oh, you belong to me.
Your skin and your organs belong to me now.
So I just need a little bit of coal so we can get the campfire going.
And I need to make a bottle.
Very important.
Okay, we're home again.
In, in.
We also gotta empty this bad boy down here.
Oh, this is gonna fill up my inventory like crazy, though.
Here.
We only got six white wool on that expedition?
Hmm.
Nuts.
For the house.
We got obsidian for the portal.
Oh, okay.
So that's why I can leave them as zero.
I can just click here and then it goes...
You know?
Yo, that's actually really nice.
That means I don't have to automatically do this every time.
I just click here when I'm out exploring, you know?
Let's say I put the most...
Yo!
Hold on.
I just figured out the perfect use case for this toolbox.
What do you always get when you're exploring?
You get this crap.
You get this.
You know?
You get all these little annoyances.
So whenever you're annoyed, you pull out the toolbox.
Boom.
And everything goes in.
How genius is that?
No more annoyances.
That's much better.
I'm happy about that.
Yeah.
What did I want to do just now?
Oh, yeah.
I needed to make a campfire, so that means coal.
I'll just need one of those.
And for the campfire, what did I need?
Locks and sticks.
Sticks I have.
And locks I also have.
Just grab one, two, three.
Campfire.
Done.
And now we need a bottle.
Three glass.
Doot, doot, doot.
Nice.
Okay.
And that's about it, I think.
Campfire bottle.
Yep.
Cool.
Let's go.
And I remember exactly where the bee is.
I think there.
Black sheep.
Okay.
I'll leave some sheep alive.
You know, it's nice to just have some...
I don't know.
Some life around me.
Makes it less lonely.
There it is.
The question now is, where exactly does this need to be?
Is it like right above it?
Or below it, I mean?
It's definitely making nasty noises now.
Yes!
Let me get more.
Oh, I can't.
Okay.
Sick.
I wasn't paying attention just now.
Did actually...
Did something actually...
Okay.
Well, I think I need more honey.
Also, I can't just pick up my campfire like that.
You have to reassemble it.
But hey, we got some charcoal out of it.
So really, I can just do this.
Like that.
Yeah, and crafting...
Oh, man.
Fuck.
You know what?
Let's just go back and grab the...
the extra crafting table.
And when I get...
pick it up and take it with me, we're gonna pick up the...
the bee house, and we're gonna take it with us.
And we're gonna have it at home.
Can't wait to have bees at home.
Maybe I'll have like a luxury...
bee house, you know?
Like, with all the trimmings.
They're gonna have flowers all around.
They're gonna have their little own...
door.
It's gonna be like insanely overkill.
But just for the bees.
Wouldn't that be fun?
I think it would be fun.
There it is.
Actually, we don't need to bring that.
We do need to bring that.
We can make more as we go.
And sticks we already have.
That's great.
Let me just make it here.
Campfire.
Make two of them.
I have two more bottles.
That's perfect, because I saw two more bee homes up there.
One there, and some are over there as well.
Yes.
That's good.
Go.
I like how, like, razor-focused I've been today, man.
I'm getting shit done.
No distractions.
Just pure, focused gameplay.
Like, think about it.
We, uh, we got all the animals that we needed.
They are now in our enclosure.
We got obsidian.
We got wool.
I'm freaking ready.
And then we're gonna go to the nether soon.
Maybe I'll...
Wait.
Oh, I thought I could, you know, uh, shave that.
Make it into, like, a jaggle liner or something.
I have a memory of that.
Okay, so this is the one we already did.
It's empty.
We took all the bee honey.
I think...
Where did I come down?
I came down, like, over there-ish.
So it was definitely up here.
Watch me find it.
It's right up here.
Ah!
Bee spotted!
Where's your home?
Wait, there's more up there as well.
There it is.
Wait, is it empty?
It doesn't even look like it's full.
Wait.
No, it's empty, isn't it?
Shit!
Why won't they make honey?
Man, what?
Okay, there's more up there.
Let's check that.
There's actually so many bees here.
Where's your home?
There.
Show me the honey.
No!
Wait, I need to confirm.
This can't be right.
No, it's that...
No, man.
No!
Oh!
He plopped into it right now.
Jesus Christ.
Dude, this is a nice view, huh?
What an area!
The more I see of it, the more I love it.
Come on, you've been in there all night.
You surely have made honey.
How can I egg them on?
Like...
Oh!
Yeah, come on!
Come on!
Show me!
Show me the honey!
Assholes!
Okay, well, that was one more...
Uh...
Somewhere over here.
We have one more shot at this.
There.
Why are there so many bees here?
Like bee country.
It's all...
Wait, why is that...
Also empty?
Okay, I know why, actually.
You know why the other one was not empty?
It's because it was in range of my base.
Which means...
They have had time to accumulate all the honey.
These ones were out of range of the base.
So, yeah.
That's a bummer.
But maybe, since we've been here before...
Another bee over there?
Maybe this one, by now, has accumulated.
I just want these bees to assimilate, you know?
Wait, where...
Okay.
Mission get honey failed.
Unfortunately.
But on the way back, I will quickly check the first one...
And see if that one has finally filled up.
If not...
GG.
I'll have to try and...
Actually, you know what?
Let me try this.
I'm going to take this with me.
Can I?
Oh!
Oh, shit.
I'm sorry.
I apologize!
Fucking hell.
Ow, ow, ow.
Yeah, I need to take it up and pick it with me.
I can't do it.
It ain't working.
Let me see your home.
Show me your home.
Did you make honey for me?
You did not!
Damn.
Ah, shit.
Okay, but maybe the first one down here now has honey.
And who knows?
Maybe this whole honey endeavor is a dead end anyway.
I'm pretty much just assuming here.
Oh, wait!
There's another one back there!
Look!
That one could definitely have had time...
...to assimilate.
Show me the honey!
Fuck!
Now I have to kill a tree!
God damn it!
Look what you made me do!
Boom.
Okay, now.
Right there.
Don't mind if I do!
Wait, I could have just leave this here.
But that's probably gonna make them not wanna make honey.
Let's not do that.
Maybe there's one more?
Maybe.
One last one?
For the road?
Because I was in this area chopping trees, remember?
So I've spent time here.
Man, you're all very killable right now.
But I'm not gonna do it.
We have sheeps at home.
Look for the bees.
No bees.
Okay, well that's good.
We got a little bit of honey.
And maybe we can do something with that now that we have two bottles of it?
Would be nice if we had a bee home very close to home over here somewhere.
And maybe we do, actually.
I should really just take a quick look around, see if I see some bees next to my home.
Let's check this way.
Bees?
What?
How dare you poop on my lawn?
No.
Okay.
Oh.
Thought there was a bee home.
Also, there's an actual word for that, and I'm not remembering it.
Bee something.
Hey, guys!
I have come to slaughter you.
Actually, not yet.
It's not yet time.
Okay, can we do something with this honey?
Something that is miraculous, maybe.
Ooh, yeah.
I like the look of that.
But that's not exactly what I was looking for.
Block cutting.
Dude, I should get into this.
I should cut some blocks!
Wait, what?
Ooh.
Copycat panel.
What is a copycat step, even?
Like, hold on.
Converts any full block into a decorative step.
And right-click applies health item as its material, if possible.
Click again to cycle orientation or powered state.
Use a wrench to reset the material.
Hmm.
So I can turn this...
Oh, so wait.
This is like...
A template.
So let's say I want to make it wooden.
I put wood on it, and now, boom.
We got a wooden flapjack.
That's interesting.
Copper table.
Dude, this looks sick!
I want to make this!
Copper bar.
Wait, copper bars?
Oh!
Right.
I think of the ingots when I see that.
Block up...
Dude!
Let's try this!
Iron ingot?
Hold on.
We have a...
We have a thing.
Where?
There.
Wait, how does this work?
The other way.
How do I make it, uh...
Dude.
Why would I ever want to saw down?
Come on!
There we go.
Okay, so this one...
Okay, we got an axle there.
Man, why is it always the opposite of what I have that I need?
You know what I mean?
Um...
Oh, man.
Oh, actually!
No!
It's super easy.
Super easy!
Watch this!
Mega easy!
We already have it.
Right there!
It's spinning.
But it's not...
Spinning?
Is it too slow?
Oh, God!
Stop!
Oh!
Ah!
Woo!
Okay, that hurts!
Yeah!
Workshops most feared.
Wait.
Um...
What did I just get?
Oh, birch planks.
Whoops.
Okay, but...
Ah!
Interesting.
Hold on.
I think I need to see something.
Make some room here.
There we go.
Uh...
Da-da-da-da-da-da...
Let me actually read this.
Upward-facing mechanical saws can process a variety of items.
Yes.
Okay.
Got it.
The processed item always moves against the rotational input to the saw.
Right.
So you spin the other way.
Yep.
Okay.
Saws can work in line with mechanical belts.
Man, I wish I could make that!
How the...
Wait.
Okay, so it obviously needs, like, a cog.
And some kind of...
Oh, man.
It's totally rubber.
Right?
We need glue!
That's what we need.
We need the green stuff.
Yeah.
Or the honey, somehow.
I don't know.
Yeah.
Saws can work...
Yeah, okay, okay.
So it's gonna cut to stone.
When an ingredient has multiple possible outcomes, the filter slot can specify it.
Mmm...
Got it.
So how does it handle, uh...
If it's just random?
How does it get determined?
Without filter, the saw would cycle through all outcomes instead.
Okay, so it's just as...
Okay.
So it is kind of predictable.
It's not random.
Cutting trees.
We know about this one.
Yep.
Whenever saws are moved as part of an animated contraption.
Yeah?
I would love to try something like this.
It will cut any trees the contraption runs them into.
Mm-hmm.
Do I know what this is?
I don't know what that is yet.
Linear chassis!
I know how to make that.
This is a...
Wait.
I think this is one thing.
Maybe I just need to make a piston, actually.
Maybe that's the link I need to unlock that.
Inventories attached to the contraption will pick up their drops automatically.
Okay.
Does that also work that way if it's not part of an animated contraption?
So they go in.
Even if they spread all over?
Because they kind of fall all over, right?
Okay, well.
Cool.
Uh, yes.
We gotta figure out how to make those belts, man.
This has to be, like, a priority now.
Do I know something about glue?
I don't, I don't think.
No.
Hmm.
We got a birch door out of it.
Obsidian.
Let's go to the nether now!
I'm ready.
We have the golden helmet.
We are totally ready.
On with that.
I don't think we need to bring a crank for this.
We're not gonna crank anything.
Honey bottle.
Um, yeah.
Put this stuff in here.
For now.
These random ass little items are gonna be annoying.
Let's go to the bit.
Oh, shit.
Oh, you suck!
No shield.
Easy.
Now we sleep.
Cheers.
I've got a bone.
Oh, we should totally mix this.
I mean, uh, mill it.
Bop, bop, bop.
Can I mill a chicken?
Boom.
No, okay, okay.
Would be kind of cool to make chicken soup.
Or something.
Put charcoal in here.
Level 26, by the way.
So wait, let me think.
Uh, I need bookshelves to make enchanting work.
Books, and books can be made from paper.
Oh!
But can it also not be made differently?
Because this is not, uh, normal.
Maybe you just don't have that recipe yet.
So books...
Leather.
It's leather, isn't it?
Book.
But why won't it...
Hold on.
I know the recipe for this.
Paper, paper, paper.
Wait a second.
Uh, show me.
Paper.
Sugar cane.
Right!
I have some!
There's another way?
What?
Why did the other one...
Oh, I have to right click, of course.
Wait, what?
What is that?
Oh my god!
I just unlocked a bunch of shit!
Holy...
Let's see here.
White nameplate.
Declare the name of your simulated contraption.
Edit the displayed name on the nameplate.
Changes the color.
Locks the name.
Okay.
Sandpaper.
Huh!
Can be used to refine materials.
The process can be automated with a deployer.
When used...
Applies polish to items held in the offhand or lying on the floor when looking at them.
When looking at them?
Oh, okay, I see.
Yeah.
Just target them and do it.
Okay.
Clipboard!
Keeps your notes and makes you look more professional.
When right clicked, opens the interface.
Sneak click to place it on a surface?
When used on blocks, some block settings, such as filters, can be copied with right click and applied with left click.
What?
I gotta make this.
Alloy and planks.
I got it.
You kidding me?
This sounds amazing.
Clippy!
Ha ha ha ha!
Yo!
Hold on.
Oh, I like this way more.
Hold on a minute.
We gotta...
We gotta transfer our notes.
Andesite, lava, obsidian, wool.
Can I...
Ah!
What a feature!
That is sick!
Very nice!
Oh, I can even...
Ah, that's funny.
I can even do this.
With shift click.
What if I do this?
Gonna be bold?
No?
Okay.
Maybe...
I select this?
Control U?
No.
Control I?
Okay.
Just testing.
Uh, alrighty.
This is amazing.
Obsidian we got.
Lava we got.
Yay, dude!
This...
Okay, fuck this...
We don't want that.
This is my new love.
Fuck the other thing.
This is what it's all about.
And I can put it on things?
Oh, dude!
This is such a good feature.
I'm in love with that.
Good job.
Wow.
That is massive.
Right up my alley, you know?
Okay, but there's more.
An altitude sensor.
And of course, mushroom stew.
That's definitely for flying.
And cartography table.
I wonder if this will do anything new.
I don't think it will.
Ah, here we go.
That's right.
I need a couple more obsidians just for this as well.
Uh, and diamonds.
Okay, very good progress there.
We gotta make a portal to the nether now.
That means we need a thing to light it on fire.
Flint.
Iron ingots.
Do we even have flint?
No, but I have gravel.
And you can definitely do things with gravel, right?
Let me see here.
Hey, yo, wait, that's a guaranteed one.
Dude.
The mill?
It's crazy.
And we also just got a bunch of bone meal.
Put it in there.
Oh, wait, uh, control.
No!
Okay, try again.
Mill it up!
This is so good.
Unbelievable.
I can't wait to have pipes going everywhere, you know?
And doing things...
with the pipes.
Okay, let's go feed the animals.
Need some seeds for that, and some wheat.
Eat!
Come on, let's go, let's go.
Everyone eats.
You eat, you eat, everyone eats.
Who else needs one?
I'll be good here?
Huh?
You wanna eat?
Nice.
Okay!
I think that about does it.
So where do we make the portal?
Oh!
Uh, we need this first.
Did I get it?
I did.
For flint.
So with the flint, um...
Then we needed, uh...
Here we go, I can make it.
Nice!
Let's have the portal...
Hmm.
What's a good spot for it?
It can't be too close, you know?
Because it's making noise, and I don't like that.
We can have it back here.
On the other side of the house.
Right now it's a temporary portal spot.
Do you mind, uh...
Thank you.
One, two, three, four.
There it is.
Hoi!
Are we ready?
Wait.
I have seeds that I don't need.
Do I have gold?
We have gold.
Check.
Okay.
Oh, we really need a bow, though.
We should make a bow real fast.
I do have some arrows, or the capability of making them, now that I have flint and feathers.
Gimme.
Can I...
How do I...
Did I get them all?
Um, I don't know.
I feel like I should have more than three.
I put in, like, 17.
But okay.
Odd.
Okay, so feathers.
Man, we should have more than three flint.
What the hell is happening?
Is it not a guarantee?
Gravel becomes flint.
Maybe it's more than one gravel or something.
And I only used one flint to make the flint and steel.
That's weird.
Oh, wait!
I have gravel in my inventory, dude!
Ah!
There we go.
Unbelievable.
I wish there was a way to just take out the result and not everything.
But I guess you can just wait for it to be finished.
That is the correct procedure.
I actually have some arrows already.
So the bow itself needs string.
Which we have here.
And sticks, which I think we have.
Very good.
Oh, that's my bow keybine as well.
Lovely.
Did you just break my farm?
He trampled on it!
You saw that, right?
I caught him.
I saw what you did.
We don't need this right now.
We also don't need this helmet, technically.
We don't need the bed in the nether.
This one can also stay at home.
But over here.
Clipboard comes with me.
Maybe some more torches, actually.
So we don't get lost in the nether.
That is actually important.
Ah, torches is just this.
64 is more than enough.
Are you done yet?
Not yet.
Okay.
We're gonna wait for that to be finished.
And then we're super ready for the nether.
Ideally, we would have fire protection potions.
But you can't really do that without going to the nether first.
Right?
Because you wanna get the stuff you need for that there.
Speaking of potions...
Uh...
Potion...
No, brewing...
Stand...
Brewing stand required...
Diamonds...
Uh...
I think...
I actually forgot.
I forgot what that needed.
But if we find a village, we can easily steal one.
It's no problem.
Come on!
We definitely need to speed up these wheels.
15?
Not bad.
Oh, sticks.
Stick me.
Oh!
There we go!
One stag is more than enough.
Wonderful.
Now, remember, it's not enchanted, so this bow is hella weak.
That's the problem right now.
But, it's better than nothing.
We have the shield.
Check.
Toolbox.
Is it empty?
It is.
Good.
Okay.
I think that about does it.
Let's-a go.
Keep the bed here.
We're also gonna click this real quick.
There we go.
In case we die.
I'm ready.
Man, it's been a while.
Let's go.
Oh, oh, shit.
Okay.
Straight into it.
Oh, two hits!
No problem.
Hey, what's up, bro?
Fuck the dude!
I am a master of the end.
I mean, the nether.
But also the end.
You'll see.
That's how you do it.
I immediately enter and I slab ass.
I slab ass.
Where's that from?
Slab ass.
Oh.
It's from, uh...
Key and peel.
Ha ha ha ha.
I'm taking this?
Wait, that's new!
I saw something new already.
Oh, there's all kinds of new shit!
What else?
Dude.
Okay, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Already, this is...
a great start.
We gotta be ultra careful not to fall in lava.
This is a thing that can easily happen in here.
I will never die.
Um...
What is...
That's new.
That's a new material right there.
But I'm afraid of going over there.
Let's go!
Actually, I'm gonna mine all this.
I know how valuable it is.
We also get a lot of experience.
It's just a...
a big ol' W.
God, it feels good to be in the nether again.
I've missed it!
Are you...
Oh!
Dude, we should give these guys gold.
Oh, but I don't have any.
I'll come back with gold.
Later.
Are you angry?
You're okay with me doing this, right?
It's not gold that I'm collecting.
Calm down!
You're not gonna hurt me.
Nice.
Wait, what is this?
Oh, ghast here!
Sick!
Also, I really should be getting some netherrack.
Just...
Oh!
Almost walked into that.
Just for some ascension here.
And, you know, emergency situations.
We need this!
Let's get this.
Actually, I don't trust like that.
That's gotta give me something new, right?
Oh, yeah.
We can make the arrows now.
That is wonderful!
Uh-oh.
Is it falling down?
Please don't fall down.
I need more ascension.
Oh, we also...
We gotta find the, um...
The purple mushroom...
Uh...
Some kind of word.
Oh!
Damn, you scared me, brother!
Oh, my God.
I'm a master.
I am actually unbeatable.
I wonder if these guys will become aggressive if I bonk them with my cardboard.
Guys, we have to try it.
It's a science experiment.
Are you ready?
I'm ready to leave.
Worst case.
Bonk.
Ay!
Yo, we're friends!
Sick!
Look at that!
What's up, guys?
Having a meeting?
Bonk, bonk, bonk!
Wait, I can kill them without...
Them getting angry at me?
I just discovered the ultimate technique, guys.
They take damage from fall damage.
This is it!
Get up here, guys!
Wait, are you...
Oh!
No, you're still friends!
We're friends!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Watch this.
We're gonna make it a little...
A little better down here.
Watch this.
Hey, guys!
Look what I got for you!
Oh!
He walked out of there!
Okay.
Fine.
I don't like the way they're running towards me like that.
Makes me nervous.
So what the hell is this?
Scorchia?
Scorched Earth?
Oh!
Nether music!
I've missed it!
We get nether music.
Taking a bit of everything here.
Are we good?
Oh, yeah.
Oh!
Hey!
Look!
It's perfect.
Oh, my God.
I'm telling you.
My house location is...
Insane.
I have everything I need.
I have easy access to the nether.
I have a fortress right down there.
It's just waiting for me to enter.
And I will take their stuff.
It will be glorious.
But I gotta be careful.
I can't fall down into the lava now.
We gotta make a little path.
A path along the side of the mountain.
Or whatever you want to call this.
I don't think they have mountains down here.
But something like it.
You know what I mean.
I am making my way over there.
It's actually so nice.
Dude.
It doesn't get better.
Gonna make a nice little path here.
Do we trust?
Maybe we just go down now.
Okay.
Not quite.
We're gonna go a little further.
Shit!
Oh, no.
I reacted too slow.
We put a stop to that.
Oh.
Okay.
We're good.
Uh-huh.
I'm not afraid.
Oh, man.
Okay.
So, shall we guesstimate?
That's like there.
A little further.
I don't...
Ooh, I don't like this.
Let's just put a stop to that.
Right here.
Am I aligned?
Yes or no?
I say I am perfectly aligned.
Now we go down.
Okay.
We're not perfectly aligned.
But it's close.
Lock that off again.
We got new blocks here!
Blackstone.
That's not new.
Fucking reaction times of a master.
Because that's what I am.
Are you ready?
We're gonna emerge right on top of their heads.
And we will kill them until they die from it.
And there's nothing they can do to stop me.
Because I'm right here.
Here I come.
Here's Johnny!
That's right, bitch!
Bring it on!
Don't forget to put torches.
Uh-oh.
Got him.
Definitely looting him.
Oh, I don't like this.
Oh, shit!
Where did that come from?
What the fuck, brother?
My goodness!
Did I drop something in panic just now?
I feel like I just dropped something.
Hey!
What's happening?
What's up, bro?
Dude, this- This bow sucks ass!
He's right up there.
Ow.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
Ow!
Fuck!
Where?
I'm dying!
I'm okay.
Okay.
We gotta get this loot.
Hey, guys.
Thank you.
I need your Balsam.
Give me your Balsam Eco.
Oh, bup, bup, bup, bup.
Okay, I may... Oh, no, he's back.
We got skeletons.
I need to play this strategic.
We can't engage.
Okay, hide back here for now.
I thought
I had full health.
I couldn't tell my HP.
Shit, man.
No!
Piss off!
Where'd he go?
Did he go in?
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh, you wanna dance?
You wanna dance?
Oh.
Fuck!
I misclicked.
Wait, I have no gold on!
Wait, I can't jump!
I'm gonna die!
Dude, this is the worst combination of all time!
I have an idea.
Oh, no, I don't... Fuck.
I wish there was water in there.
Wait.
No.
Fuckin' hell!
I knew that was gonna happen!
Why did I do so much damage?
I had armor on!
Like...
Oh, no.
Oh, fuck me, dude.
Okay, calm down.
Just focus now.
We can easily...
Easy, easy.
We know what to do.
Hey!
Fuck!
Okay.
Where did we die?
Was it...
It was in there.
Get it.
Eat.
Quick!
Food, food, food, food, food, food, food!
Fuck!
Oh, we're safe.
We're safe.
Shield, shield.
Oh.
Where did that guy even come from?
Like, he fell from...
The sky.
What's up with that?
Wow.
Alright.
Well, that was unfortunate, you know?
It happens, though.
I feel like it doesn't count, though, because it's in the nether.
It's like...
It's different.
Let's go...
Here.
I'm going this way.
Actually, put it there instead.
Oh, dude!
I lost all my levels!
I was level 30!
Fuck!
Man, what a bummer.
Hey, at least I got my stuff back.
Okay, level 10.
I cannot get lost in here.
That would be the ultimate mistake.
Okay, I...
You cannot underestimate the nether.
Like, this place is...
Insane.
It's back here.
Dead end?
Dude, my pickaxe is about to break.
The good news is, I think we're coming back with a lot of new stuff, you know?
And we can sit there and experiment.
Oh, man.
Okay.
This way.
I have gold on.
So we're pals, right?
High five.
Yes.
Sup, bro?
Wait, what?
I had a shield up!
Fuck you.
Alright.
We gotta look for, uh, potion thingies.
Worms word.
Or whatever.
Oh, crap.
These guys are actually kind of insane.
Play it safe.
Kill them from a distance.
Did he fall down?
Hey!
Hey, look at me!
Come over here!
Sucker.
Anything in here?
Nope.
Let me actually block that off.
Okay, so this entire section has been checked.
Nothing there.
Hey, I need a blaze rod.
Would you give me one?
I don't think he dropped one.
Okay, let's see what's in here.
Are they spawning up there?
Oh, yeah.
That looks promising.
Let's do a little, uh, this.
Sup, fool?
I can't hit.
I'm terrible.
Wow.
Oh, shh.
Oh!
Stop.
Got him.
Wait, did the other one die?
We got one.
I'm happy with that.
I saw you in there.
I see you.
Trying to dark souls me!
Fuck.
I hate not knowing where this is coming from.
We're also running low on meat.
Look at that gang down there!
Oh!
Fuck.
Can I shoot through here?
No.
Boom.
One kill.
One shot, one kill.
Boom.
That was amazing!
Blaze rods!
They shall be mine.
Thanks.
I'm not leaving until I have Wormswort.
This may look like the place, actually.
What's up, bro?
Oh!
Shit!
That's a lot.
There's a lot back there!
They had a whole ambush waiting.
Okay.
I don't care about you.
I need to find...
Oh!
Here we go!
That's it!
What is it called?
Nether ward.
That's right.
Alright!
We're leaving.
I'm done here.
Think I came from here?
Yep.
Oi!
It wasn't me!
Kill him!
Dude, why are there so many skeletons on my way out?
How many arrows left?
15.
I almost fell down!
Wait, we got a black skeleton!
Run!
Holy crap, broly!
What's up, brother man?
Let it be known as the day you almost caught!
The master himself.
Oh.
Actually, uh...
Where did I even come from?
I still have more skeletons.
This is not good.
Wait, I'm going the wrong way!
I don't know where I'm going.
Why are there so many of them?
Where the hell did I come from?
I have no...
I have no food.
Oh, wait!
It's here!
Oh, it's right here, dude!
It's right here!
Oh, my God!
Yes!
Oh!
That feels amazing!
Oh, we made it!
Let's get the hell out of here.
I got the goods!
Leave me alone.
See ya, suckers!
Actually, I'm taking this.
I'm a little greedy.
Get out of my way.
Good enough.
Can't be too greedy, though.
You got to know your limits.
Don't mind me.
Coming through.
Hot soup!
Oh!
Man.
You are still here!
I know he didn't go through!
Because that takes time.
I don't know.
I feel like he's bugging out.
Sleep.
Oh, man.
That was so close.
I was so close to losing everything.
Horrible.
Let's see what we actually came home with.
I'm gonna take a quick break after that, guys.
I need a moment.
I'll see you in a little bit.
Man, I am so glad I took that break.
I really needed to just walk around a bit after that.
My heart was in my throat.
And now it's back where it belongs.
In my chest.
Okay.
So.
New pickaxe?
For sure.
Because this one's about to be gone.
In fact, I don't want to play with you anymore.
Good.
We got bones.
Let's mill the shit out of that.
And...
Oh!
We got a bunch of stuff here.
Let's see.
You ready?
Here we go.
Yes!
We definitely want to make that.
Maybe I shouldn't have used all that on the arrows.
Maybe there was something else I could have made.
Another word block, huh?
We can make one of those.
I hate it.
Put it back.
Ah, shit.
This...
Rose quartz.
That seems good.
Nice.
And then we need it.
That's pretty much what we need it, right?
Rose...
Quartz!
Okay.
What?
I don't know.
So we can cut it?
Wait a minute.
Bring back the cutter.
Shit.
Dude, how do I freaking place this?
There we go.
How did...
Why is this not spinning?
Should that not be spinning?
Or is that just me?
Here we go!
Wow.
A block of rose quartz.
I got two of them.
Okay.
What's that for, though?
What else is new?
Empty blaze burner.
Iron sheet and netherrack.
I can make that.
I've got it, baby.
What was it called?
Empty blaze burner.
Oh, we definitely got to ponder on that.
Right-click ablaze with the empty burner to capture it!
What?
No way.
Alternatively, blazes can be collected from their spawners directly.
Oh, yeah?
Wait, I take...
I take it with me?
You now have an ideal heat source for various machines.
Okay.
I like it.
For aesthetic purposes, empty blaze burners can also be lit using flint and steel.
Oh!
Okay, so like, um...
A little bonfire.
The flame can be transformed using a soul-infused item.
Okay.
However, without a blaze, they are not suitable for industrial heating.
I see.
It's just for looks.
Cool.
Empty blaze burner.
Yeah, because we haven't caught this guy yet.
Well, guys, we gotta go back to the nether!
We have a mission now!
We gotta capture something!
Oh, wait.
Oh, there we go!
Right, the blaze rod is what we needed for that.
Okay.
And now we also have the nether wart, so we are actually kinda cooking.
Did I get any of that, uh...
Oh, I didn't get any of the cream.
Unfortunately.
Blaze powder?
We can make some of that.
Yeah.
I have ender...
Oh, yes!
Wait.
Uh, what was that called?
Cream?
Wait, what?
This is new, right?
This I don't remember at all.
I feel like I could only get this from...
from the enemies.
Yeah.
I think so.
Oh, what was that?
Ah.
Fire charge.
A brick fence.
Oh, I need four honey bottles for that.
Okay.
Comparator.
I mean, we're slowly unlocking more, uh, redstone stuff.
Oh, I wanted to make a hopper, didn't I?
I mean, a piston.
Because I think this will unlock something for me.
Redstone dust, iron ingots, cobblestone.
Oh, that's a lot of stuff.
Uh, cobblestone.
Iron ingots.
Um, piston.
Wood.
Don't I have something easy?
I can...
Maybe this one.
Come on.
No?
Aw, man.
Okay.
Whatever.
I thought for sure that would unlock something.
All right.
Let me actually, um...
I'm just testing here.
Oh.
Uh, I could do this though, right?
Hey, okay.
Not bad.
This can be a little decorative, um...
Uh, bonfire in here, you know?
Right there, for now.
Let's have a couple...
Uh, chairs around that.
I think I have some lying around.
I don't.
But I will have.
That's all I need.
Yeah.
This is temporary, of course.
Look at that!
Ah!
Oh!
We gotta finish this house as well, man.
We need to have a home.
I'm gonna put this here.
Wool.
Still haven't gotten that.
I love the clipboard.
Nothing else I can do with those blaze rods.
Oh, I guess I can make the...
Yeah.
Brewing stand.
Let's make it.
Let's put that inside the house for now.
Let's have it over...
here.
One of them.
And...
Now we need bottles.
Which means glass.
15 bottles.
And maybe I'll also make a little chest.
To go along with it.
Yeah.
Give me this one.
Just so we can have some brewing stuff next to it, you know?
But hold on.
I also saw something else in here.
Yeah.
We gotta capture the guy.
Mysterious conversion.
Wait a sec.
Automated brewing.
Hey!
Look!
Blaze burner.
So wait.
I would still need to somehow bring the stuff inside though, right?
Ingredients and liquid.
So I guess I would need pipes.
And I'm assuming also the...
Oh man.
The thing...
The belt.
Right?
So we need a belt that transports items in.
And a liquid.
So pipes.
How'd that work?
So water?
You bring in water?
It's made in stages though, right?
Heat it.
Okay.
I do want to make some fire protection potions though.
So I gotta go get some magma cream.
And I also gotta go back anyway.
So we can collect those guys.
Alright, what about food?
How are we doing on that?
Let's make some more.
Mutton.
Put these in here.
No.
Keep that...
No, yeah.
Keep it in here.
What about that nether quartz?
Is there really nothing else I could make?
Make a chute.
Dude, let's make a minecart.
I have a feeling that's gonna unlock something.
Minecart.
Come on.
Oh.
No, wait.
That's new.
That's not new.
Okay.
Alright.
I need more chests here.
Two more.
Let's put exotic items in here.
Like, really ex...
This is exotic.
Actually, nether wart belongs in that other place.
Damn, it's glowstone dust.
Gas tier...
Is actually also used here.
This is...
Exotic.
What else is exotic?
None of this is exotic.
Already done cooking.
Man, the smoker is fast.
Oof.
Some speed on that one.
Some more coal as well.
In fact, put it in there.
Minecart is not needed right now.
See, I kind of want to throw some stuff away here.
Like, this stuff, I don't want it.
Not right now.
Coarse dirt.
Who needs that?
Not me.
One slab.
Boo.
Get out of here.
Right?
Diorite.
Boo.
Absolutely not.
That's it.
I'll keep these arrows.
Put that on.
Okay, so we probably need a little bit more arrows.
Lent.
I think I ran out.
Dang it.
Iron ingot goes in here.
Gunpowder is in here.
I forgot to use my toolbox.
For things.
Now, 18 arrows is fine.
I just need...
I just gotta go get a blaze boy.
It shouldn't be too hard.
What's up, bro?
It looks like there's...
I picked up my shit!
Ugh!
That is so annoying.
No, keep the bones.
Ah!
Pain.
Pure pain.
Suffering.
We don't need to fill the steel right now.
Yeah.
Are we good?
I think we're good.
Ascension.
Oh, we need this thing in here, of course.
Gotta bring this with us.
I am so ready.
I love capturing things.
Adding it to my collection.
We're going back into the nether.
And we're also gonna get some magma cream.
This is the current mission.
There's gonna be a skeleton in here?
Yep!
I saw that coming a mile away.
Let's not run, because we don't have a lot of food.
Let's go chill.
The problem is, getting back here is gonna be a little annoying now.
I need a faster way up.
You know what?
I am going to...
No.
No, no, no.
It's fine.
Let's go get one.
I'm not gonna waste my arrows.
Here we...
Oh, there's a lot over there.
Maybe too many.
I need them to shoot at me.
Come on.
Dodge that one.
Yike!
Haha!
Hee hee hee!
See ya!
Yup, yup, yup, yup, yup, yup!
Bye-bye!
Actually, hold on.
I'm not leaving yet.
I am leaving.
No!
I wanna kill these guys.
I need Magma Cream.
Oh!
Fuck you.
I thought I was out of range.
Got him.
They're still shooting at me!
Imagine if they pushed me off the edge here.
Okay, so they have almost despawned now.
We're going back.
We're...
Yeah, we're going back.
I saw a dude over there on the left.
It's okay.
That's okay.
You can try and shoot me if you want.
Oh god.
There we go!
We got something!
Yeah!
Oh!
I guess we leave.
I got what I came for.
See ya!
Wanna try and shoot me?
Nice try, brother.
Not today.
Nobody's gonna hit me.
Good.
Let's go!
This was such a successful little expedition.
Race is sharp.
I saw a guy up here, too.
Somewhere.
That I want to kill.
Would love to get a little more magma cream while I'm here.
Perhaps we got some...
magma boys somewhere.
They're usually over here, in this sort of biome, right?
They like to hang out near these lava places.
Oh yeah, this is...
No.
Hostile terrain.
No bueno.
Ah!
We got one.
Making a tiny path.
Hoy!
Wow.
I think I didn't panic.
He's right here.
Ah!
He was right there.
Don't fall down.
Gonna hit you at an angle.
Great, great, great.
Yeah, come in.
Come to me.
Come in here.
I know you want to get...
I don't want to kill you there, because you're going to fall down.
And it's not good for me.
Let me make some room for you.
There.
There we go.
Come, come here.
Come here.
Come at me, bro.
This way.
I welcome thee.
Oh shit, sorry.
Oh no.
Got him.
Hmm.
Do I even want to go here?
That's the question.
Methinks?
Maybe not.
No.
Go back.
What's this?
Scorchion.
Okay.
There are some weird blocks here.
Like...
Berydium and some other stuff.
Not really sure what to do with that.
Oh, we got another one.
Nice.
That's definitely like one magma cream.
I'm so good at that.
Oi.
He's trying to crit me.
What's up, little guys?
Oh, come on.
Not a single one?
Man.
Never lucky.
Another one there now.
Oh, there's two of them.
Luck smiles upon me.
There we go.
We got one.
What are you doing up there?
Ow.
Dude, I really need some diamond armor here.
Or even better.
Netherite armor.
I hear ghosts everywhere.
Another one?
Okay.
Hey, you.
I don't feel like leaving yet.
I actually kind of want to level up a little bit.
Level 20?
Am I seeing something?
I want to find a bastion.
I just want to locate it.
I'm not going to invade it yet.
Obviously, that's a bad idea with my current armor.
I gotta say, though, I love this part of the nether here.
It's just a very promising area, you know?
It's good.
Dude, I keep forgetting how good the Minecraft music is in the nether.
Every time I hear it, I'm like, oh yeah, right.
This thing slaps.
Thanks.
Dude, where is this ghost?
I hear it.
Is it right below me?
It's down there somewhere.
Or above me.
Could also be.
Okay, I think we're done now.
I'm happy.
Fantastic little excursion.
No, my music.
So sad.
They should let that track finish, you know?
Even if you go back here.
It's almost a crime.
So just stop it like that.
Okay.
So now that we have magma cream, we can actually make some potions.
First, we need water.
Take a couple.
Three of them.
Three magma cream is fantastic.
We needed this.
Let's see if I remember this.
So, one, two, three.
Magma cream first.
It's gonna make it awkward.
And then after that, we put in magma cream.
And then after that, we put redstone dust to extend the duration.
I should have a clipboard here with the...
Oh, that's actually so much better.
Clipboard with the ingredients, you know, for these things.
So I never forget.
And it's right next to it.
I don't have to carry a book around.
Genius.
Wait, what?
Hey, guys, I can make a clipboard when I have a clipboard.
That's crazy.
Huh?
Doesn't even make sense.
I mean, it kind of does.
It's like, hey, you have a clipboard?
That means you have a clipboard.
You're not wrong.
So that needed what exactly?
Paper and some other things?
Oak and...
And alloy.
Okay.
Paper.
What did I miss?
What?
This.
Nice.
Right there.
Magma cream.
Makes fire protection.
That's actually so cool.
So awkward.
Great.
Now we put this in.
And after that, it's nether wart.
No.
Redstone dust.
Which means I gotta bring some.
Oh, wait.
I didn't put it on the wall.
There we go.
Now it's on the wall.
Fire resistance!
Yeah!
I'm trying to see if I remember the invisibility potion now.
I'm pretty sure it's weakness potion, and then you have to put something in the weakness potion.
So you have to make the potion first, and then use that as the base for the next one.
Something like that.
There we go, baby!
Local brewery!
Is that a Minecraft thingy?
Local brewery?
Oh, yeah, it is.
Yeah.
Okay, so what else?
Let me see here.
A strong breeze!
I could try and fix that now.
I kind of want to do the achievements, you know?
Should be pretty easy to do.
I guess I just need to add more sails to it.
Here.
Make babies.
There you go.
Sorry.
You have bread.
So now it's time for me to turn you into dead.
Oh, I need a gate, actually.
Hey, you mind going away?
Wonderful!
Much better.
Potions are done.
Let's leave them in this box.
Just for now, at least.
Gas tear is also an ingredient.
Oh, uh, blaze burner.
Let me see this.
Brass ingots.
Zinc and copper.
Brass.
Huh.
Interesting.
So you...
Oh, okay.
You have to do this to make this.
Okay.
I can do that.
In fact, I can just do this.
Wait, do I need to, uh...
Wait, are you on?
You don't look like you're...
On to me.
Oh!
Ha, ha, ha.
Ah.
Fucking hell.
I don't want to cover you up, actually.
Actually, I do.
Wait, it's kind of fucked up that I took this guy captive, and now he's here just to heat my stuff.
Um...
Let me just try and put some stuff in there.
So what did that say?
Uh, this one.
Copper zinc.
Zinc.
Okay.
Copper and zinc.
Seems easy enough.
Copper.
And zinc.
Five, six.
Oh.
Are you mixing?
You're not mixing.
Do we need more?
Okay, you know what?
Let me, um...
I need to read about you.
Little bastard.
Blaze burners can provide heat to items processed in a basin.
Okay.
I get it.
Oh, really?
Huh.
I almost want to say, say no more, fam, but let's watch.
Let's keep watching.
With a blaze cake, the burner can reach an even stronger level of heat.
Oh, yeah, you want some cake?
I'll give you some cake.
The feeding process can be automated using deployers or mechanical arms.
Dude, I can't wait to make a mechanical arm.
And a belt.
I wanna...
I wanna fucking transport items.
You know?
Okay.
Got it.
So, you just need something to eat.
Easy enough.
I got you, fam.
Oh, I've got a lot of dark oak for you.
Boink.
Oh, yeah, you like that?
Mmm-hmm.
I'm giving you a full stack of it, so you're gonna be nice and hot for a long time.
Yeah.
Okay, now we cover it up.
And...
You ready?
Here we go, here we go!
Mix it up!
That's what Terry Crew says on 100 Cooks.
Every time.
I love it.
Oh!
Ah!
Okay, here we go.
Real alloys.
Alrighty.
Let me see.
Something was just flashing here.
I missed it.
Shit, I missed it.
What is new?
Brass casing.
Oh!
Okay, so it's just like...
Andesite.
Brass sheet.
Oh.
Oh, oh shit.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
You got it.
Oh, I gotta do this.
Smash it up!
What did I unlock?
Block of brass, probably?
Brass nuggets.
Whoa!
This one has no name?
Embellish your machines with this imposing wheel of brass.
When powered by kinetics, start spinning.
Okay.
A brass hand!
Why?
Hold on.
We gotta make more of this.
That's right.
Mix it up.
In fact, even more.
Oh yeah.
Dude, I want a belt so I can...
Onto this and go...
You know?
Ah!
I need to!
Go in.
I want to throw this away.
I hate it.
The rest I like.
Mill it up!
I'm gonna wait for...
No, I'm not gonna wait.
It...
Wait.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Oh, it made 32!
Nice!
And it gave me seven bags.
So it was almost done.
That's fine.
Let's go, man!
Punch it!
Let's make it a bit more.
There we go.
Oh, look at the...
Fires of industry!
We got some flint now.
Wait, how did I get flint?
Maybe it was left over from last time.
Holy crap!
We got a lot of bone meal out of that one.
Some white dye.
Exotic items.
Gunpowder.
Let's cook some meat.
Mmm.
Mmm-mmm-mmm.
Let's keep feeding these assholes.
Hey!
Make kits.
I require it.
Good.
Oh!
Oh, okay.
Ah, I'm so sorry.
It had to be the children.
I can't be arsed to put you back in there.
I'm sorry.
It's horrible.
I know.
But you did it to yourself.
By leaving.
You can't leave.
I gotta eat.
God, I love hearing the bonk.
Brass ingots.
Let's make some more.
Let's make...
A block of brass.
Which means we can turn it back, I guess.
Yep.
Wonderful.
Peculiar bell?
A decorative brass bell.
Placing it right above open soul fire may have side effects.
Is that so?
Wait, what?
Bell.
Haunted bell.
Okay.
So we gotta place it right open...
Or right above some soul fire.
And it becomes haunted bell?
A cursed bell haunted by lost souls of the nether.
When held or rang.
Highlights nearby lightless spots on which hostile mobs can spawn?
What?
That is so cool.
What the fuck, dude?
Hell yeah.
Amazing.
Okay.
We gotta make that?
How do I get soul fire, though?
Let me think.
Soul...
We can make a soul campfire, though, right?
That's a thing.
Soul...
Okay, okay, okay.
I have that.
Unless I threw it away.
No, I have it.
Soul sand.
And we need logs, or whatever.
And sticks.
Campfire.
Let's put this in the center in here.
We're gonna have a little seance, you know?
Get a little Ouija board going.
I like it.
Let me see this.
Nice.
Here we go.
Why...
How come I can't...
Hmm.
Maybe it needs to be higher up?
Hold on.
Oh, shh.
Okay.
Oh.
Interesting.
Mysterious conversion.
Placing it right above...
Open soul fire.
Maybe it needs to be...
Really high up?
Can I put it on a wall?
Probably not, right?
That doesn't even make sense.
Oh!
Never mind.
It totally makes sense.
But maybe a little further down?
Ay!
Haunted bell!
Get haunted, noob.
I see how that works.
Oh.
Fuck.
I just got a little haunted there.
Okay, we gotta...
Wait, how did that work?
When held or rang?
Oh, okay.
I'm holding it.
Cool!
But I guess it's better to just...
Start by doing this, man.
And then walk around with this and see.
But how do I...
It said just holding it would do it too.
That doesn't seem to be the case.
When held or rang?
Am I not holding it?
Wait, a minute to walk a little further.
Oh!
Okay!
Ay!
Okay, that's sick.
What a great idea.
Right here, though, right?
No?
I could have sworn this would be...
But I guess this is how you learn.
Oh.
Right here.
Let's check for weak spots around the perimeter.
Definitely, yeah.
I was about to say.
Oh, hey there.
Oh my god.
My shield is not on.
So I guess, ideally, you want to put it, like, right at the edge.
Like here.
And then you keep walking.
And as soon as you see the edge again...
Then you get the optimal placement.
Ow!
Actually, even better, you would put it in the center of whatever that is, right?
And not right at the edge.
Okay.
Let me see.
Yeah, so here's where it starts.
It's kind of impossible to calculate, I guess.
But it's, like, here, you know?
Right there, for sure.
I mean, you can also just tell by looking at how much light there is.
It's not really needed.
But it is nice for catching little...
Blind spots, right?
There we go.
That should do it.
Let me see.
Aha!
See?
That's what I mean.
Catching a little blind spot like that is nice.
That would have slipped through my perimeter.
Man, this axe right here has been going for ages.
What a champ.
And you know what the good thing about this is?
You can use it during the day.
During the night, it's a lot easier without it to just see where the light goes, right?
But during the day, it's not.
That's kind of cool.
Let's hang this here.
Somewhere.
Cool spot.
Maybe here.
That way we can go like that.
I wonder what the radius is on that.
How far does it show me?
Okay.
Very nice!
That was cool!
Great item.
Let's see what else we can do here.
Chiseled.
We can try and make one of these, I guess.
That's probably going to do something.
For that, we need a couple slaps.
Oh!
I need to try and get Prismarine as well.
I'm sure there's something to do with that.
Because in the base game, it has almost no uses.
Surely they're going to do something with that now.
Right, let me see this.
Chiseled.
Chiseled bookshelf.
Okay, it didn't do anything.
It's here.
For now.
Furniture is a little sparse, okay?
I understand.
I am going to finish this house, by the way.
I'm just...
I'm waiting for the perfect way to make these andesite floors.
That's what I want to do.
Let me actually check now.
This one.
Okay.
But can I not create it?
Somehow.
There was something else that I wanted to make here.
Then I got distracted.
What else was new?
I can make an anvil.
Actually, not a bad idea.
Takes a lot of iron, though.
Brass nuggets.
Hey, we can try and make that.
Oh!
Well, there you go.
What is that?
Hold up now.
Attribute filter.
Matches items against a set of attributes or categories.
Can be used in filter slots of creates components.
It sounds really useful.
We can turn them back into a...
Yeah.
Makes sense.
Oh, yeah.
Brass hand.
That's what I was making.
I was waiting for this.
Gimme.
Brass.
It's andesite alloy.
Almost everything does.
These days.
What the hell is this?
What am I gonna do with this?
Can I...
Can I poke you?
Hey, come here.
Oh, wait.
Maybe I need to take this off.
Nope.
Okay.
Wee-yaw.
Hey, I have a brass hand now.
That's kind of cool.
What else can I try to make?
Packager.
I could make it.
Wait, rope coupling?
String and iron nuggets.
I can make it.
I cannot make it.
I don't have string.
But I can make it.
Because I can make string.
Uh...
It was over here?
If I remember correctly?
No?
What?
Here?
Wait, hold on.
String.
Oh, it's...
The only one I didn't try.
Of course.
Wee-yaw.
And done.
We got string, baby.
I need one more.
Kind of a waste, though, to turn one white wool into string.
But these are desperate times.
They require desperate measures.
Thank you.
Now with string in hand.
What was it I was making?
I don't remember.
It was not packager.
It was...
Wait, crafter slot cover?
What?
Some recipes will require additional crafters to bridge gaps in the path.
Say what now?
Using slot covers, crafters can be set to act as an empty slot in the arrangement.
Huh.
Uh...
Well, I don't even know what I'm looking at right now.
What?
Why?
Okay.
Shared inputs created with the wrench at the back can also reach...
Okay, hold on.
This is...
I don't even know what the fuck is going on right now.
I kept me thinking about that.
A fluid valve!
We already made it.
But there was something else I was working on just now.
And then I got distracted.
What was that?
Oh, this one.
No, it was not that one.
It was...
It was one of the other ones.
We can also make this nameless item.
We can make a radial...
Did I make one of those already?
Hold on.
No, I didn't.
Let's make it.
Let's ponder on this.
Radial chassis connect to identical chassis blocks in a row.
Got it.
When one is moved by a contraption, the others are dragged with it.
But is that not already what I'm doing, but with wood over there on my windmill?
Okay, slime ball.
The side faces of a radial chassis can be made sticky.
Oh, so...
Yeah, so you put on something other than the windmill sails.
Click again to make all other sides sticky.
Okay, so you save some...
goop that way.
Sneak to take it off.
An empty hand to remove the slime.
Got it.
Block attachment utility.
Okay.
Whenever a block is next to a sticky face...
I mean, it's gonna move with it.
I understand.
Yes.
Okay.
Roger that.
Put it back.
Okay, let me see.
What the hell was I trying to craft just before?
I'm losing my mind.
What was it?
It was...
something to do with...
brass nuggets.
It was not this one.
Turn...
Dude, let's make a turntable.
Let me see.
Uses rotational force to create motion sickness?
Huh?
Hey?
What are you on about?
Oh, my inventory is already terrible.
I gotta fix it right now.
Yeah.
Put the wood in here, man.
Put the exotic stuff in here.
Put this stuff in there.
X in here.
Yep.
This one is definitely here.
String.
Zinc.
Actually, this goes.
Yep.
Okay.
So, what did you say I needed for that?
Other than the thingy?
I'm also just gonna have a general look through here.
I bet something happens if I make this.
Weighted ejector.
I haven't even tried making this, either.
Mechanical bearing.
That's for the windmill.
Analog lever.
Maybe we should just try to make a bunch of redstone components.
Like, classic redstone components.
See what happens.
Was it this one?
No.
It was something that looked like this.
Propeller!
Okay, come on.
We gotta make a propeller.
So, wait.
Hold on.
Iron sheet and a side alloy.
And what else do I want to bring?
Nothing here.
I have no idea what I was trying to make before.
That's crazy.
I'm gonna make this.
Iron sheet and a side alloy.
There we go.
Propel me!
Okay, we unlocked something.
Oh.
Oh!
Probably related to flying, I imagine.
Oh, let me see.
Hey, Jackie.
Are you about ready to eat?
What's up?
Are you ready to eat?
He wants to be a part of it.
Whisk.
Oh!
And a side propeller.
I mean...
Yo, imagine if I could make a boat!
Propeller in the water?
Tell me I can do that.
Oh, this is what I was making before!
Rope coupling!
Fuck!
Let's not forget that.
Velocity sensor.
Oh!
Alright.
Ear shift.
And that's it.
Nope.
Encased fan.
Okay.
Well, we're gonna need a bunch of shit.
Uh, shafts.
Casings.
All kinds.
Let me just grab all I have.
Let me just see if I can make something right now.
I can make this one.
Whoa!
What?
The fuck is happening?
I just unlocked everything between heaven and hell.
Okay, let's keep it going.
I like it.
There was something else.
The other propeller.
Wait.
Rope pulley!
Let's actually make this.
Wool.
Casing.
Sheet.
Easy.
Wool.
Casing.
Sheet.
I have it.
Jackie.
No!
Rope pulley!
Oh, we're gonna ponder on that.
Let's make this damn rope coupling as well.
Iron nugget string.
Nug me!
Uh.
Jackie, what is it with you, huh?
Hmm?
Okay, hold on.
Guys, I'm gonna be right back.
I'm gonna feed her real quick.
She's very hungry, apparently.
I had a feeling, uh, she wasn't actually hungry.
She just wanted to play.
But I gave her food.
She's probably gonna be back in a second here.
Okay, I forgot what I was doing, man.
No, rope pulley!
That's right.
And I was making something ropey.
A rope coupling is probably a combination, huh?
With a rope pulley?
Okay, let's see.
I need to see this one.
Okay, so what is even happening?
Rope pulleys can move blocks vertically when given rotational force.
Okay.
Amazing.
Direction and speed of movement depend on the rotational input.
Got it.
With the help of super glue, larger structures can be moved.
Yeah.
I just need to make some.
I already have an idea for an elevator.
I know exactly what to do.
Oh yeah.
Yep.
Oh yes.
Movement modes of the rope pulley.
Man, I remember my times in mechanics, man.
Back when I just started learning physics.
Pulleys were a nightmare.
Fucking pulleys.
They are so counterintuitive.
It's insane.
Whenever pulleys stop moving, the move structure reverts to blocks.
Blocks.
Okay.
But were they not blocks when they're moving?
Or what?
This behavior can be modified using the value panel.
Value panel.
It can be configured never to revert to solid blocks or only at the location it started at.
Wait, uh...
So, hold on a minute.
What do you mean?
So you put a flower?
Meaning it ignores the block down here?
Or what?
So what if I had...
So if I had wood down here, it would just go through the wood?
In this configuration?
No!
That's my idea!
I was gonna make this!
Fuck!
I was gonna...
I was...
My idea!
Fuck!
This is exactly what I had in mind.
Whenever a pulley assembles a contraption...
Yeah.
Yeah, I knew it!
I knew it!
Other pulleys on the same layer will connect to the structure.
Oh.
Okay, I didn't know that.
Obviously, but...
Cool.
I was gonna make one here too, not just three.
I was gonna have four.
They do not require to be powered.
The effect is purely cosmetic.
That's fine.
Moving pulleys is part of a contraption.
Huh?
Whenever pulleys are themselves being moved by a contraption...
Yeah?
What then?
It's attached structure will be dragged with it.
Dude, I...
I want this so bad.
Give it to me!
No!
I know how to get it.
Actually, I know how to get it.
All we need...
Is...
The frickin' green stuff.
Right?
We need the fuckin' balls.
The balls from hell.
The...
The green balls.
What was it called?
Gloop ball?
I forgot the name already.
Mind that pulleys are only movable while stopped.
Oh, so they can't go up and down at the side and up and down at the same time.
Got it.
Oh, there's no more.
Dude, I just had an idea, actually.
I know where we can get the gloop balls.
It's where we...
Started the game.
Remember, we spawned in...
Some kind of, uh, marsh.
That's the spot to find those guys, right?
It's beautiful.
It is beautiful.
That's exactly what we're gonna do.
But, wait a minute.
Uh, rope coupling.
Let's ponder that one.
No!
What?!
Right-clicking a rope winch and connect it with a rope coupling will attach them together?
Wait, what do you mean?
Can I make a drawbridge?
There's no way.
When given rotational force, rope winches reel in and...
In and out the attached rope.
Alright.
Yeah!
Come on.
Let's see it.
Ah, it's stuck.
Shears can be used to remove the rope.
Oh, yeah?
But why would I do this, then?
What's the point?
Can I attach it to...
Hold on.
I need to understand this.
Right-click holding a wrench to sl...
Whoa!
Guys!
This is amazing!
What the fuck?
That is incredible!
Alright!
I'm sold.
Let's see this one.
A pair of rope connectors can be attached with rope.
Okay.
So it's just gonna be...
It can't do anything with that.
I guess I can slide down.
A pair of rope winches cannot connect.
Okay.
Got it.
Very cool.
I also got something else.
This one.
Encased fan.
Encased fans use rotational force to create an air current.
Right.
For flying...
Strength and direction of flow depends on the rotational input.
But wait a minute.
Is this actually connected to the flying stuff?
Because we had a bunch of other things.
Where was the propeller at?
There was one more thing I wanted to make.
Was not a spring.
Wait.
Nozzle?
What even is this?
Ay!
Attacks to the front of an encased fan!
To distribute its effects on entities in all directions?
That was actually not the one I was thinking of.
But let's make it.
Hell yeah!
Kind of want to make this wheel.
With no name.
Shaft and ingots.
I have a lot of those.
Wait.
What is the na- Is this called a wheel?
Wait a minute.
If I write wheel...
Is it called brass wheel?
Wheel of brass?
Maybe a brasserie?
I'm kidding.
Okay.
It's a wheel.
What the hell is this?
It's a big old wheel.
Alright.
Put it in here.
Okay.
Well, I wasn't done reading this, actually.
So we had this.
This.
When passing through lava, the airflow becomes heated.
Huh.
Okay.
Interesting.
What is the point of...
Is that like air balloons or something?
Hot air?
Items caught in the area will be smelted?
Hold on.
Items?
Or enemies?
That's the first thing I think of.
What do you mean smelted?
That's some hot air.
Food items thrown here would be incinerated.
Oh.
You know what, uh...
Like, the mobs are made of?
Meat.
So what...
What would logically happen to the mobs?
Instead, a setup for smoking using fire should be used for them.
Oh, right.
Okay, I see.
That's the difference.
Lava, fire.
Air flows passing through water create a washing setup?
Wait, what are you talking about?
Some interesting new processing can be done with it.
Yeah, I can turn my smelly jeans into fresh and delicate smelling jeans.
The speed of the fan does not affect the processing speed.
Only its range.
Okay.
I immediately need to try this.
Immediately.
Fan processing can also be applied to items on depots and belts.
Oh, so like a, uh...
Like a factory setup, right?
Dude, we're gonna have stages.
We're gonna have stages.
Ha!
Ha ha!
Okay!
So wait, what's that just happened there?
You wash the sand and it becomes...
Is that clay?
Looks like a clay thingy.
Moving simulated contraptions using nozzles.
That's the one I just got!
Hold the phone.
What am I looking at?
This looks...
Amazing.
What even is this?
What the fuck?!
Nozzles attached to fans on simulated contraptions push away from nearby surfaces.
Is that a freaking, uh...
Hover machine?
Kind of looks like that thing that, uh...
NASA astronauts would train with before they went to the moon.
You know, the...
The lunar module.
It's a little too long, but if it was a little shorter, that's exactly what this looked like.
You know?
No safety at all.
It was super dangerous.
Nearby walls will be pushed away from horizontally.
Oh, okay.
But this...
How the...
How is this even gonna work, though?
Fluids also act as a surface.
Right.
Dude, can I make a helicopter?
I mean...
Maybe.
Okay, okay, okay!
Sick!
Insane knowledge here.
Polk washing.
Really?
Oh!
Right!
Oh, you wash off the paint!
That makes so much sense.
Hey!
We can finally kill...
Colored sheep!
No more only white killings!
This is amazing!
We can turn it back into white wool!
Nice!
Gravel!
Wait, what?
Becomes flint and...
Iron nugget!
Oh, it's like looking for gold!
You know how you, uh...
You grab a handful of gravel from the river?
You shake it in your hand through the...
You know, the thingy?
And it, uh...
You find the little valuables.
That's cool.
What?!
We can turn that into obsidian!
By washing it!
So that means magma blocks were always obsidian?
They were just dirty!
Dirty obsidian!
Yeah, clay ball, I saw that.
Soul sand...
Nether quartz...
And gold nugget.
There's gold in...
Oh, I guess that makes sense!
Because we see a bunch of gold in the nether embedded in all this stuff.
You know?
That is amazing!
And look at this!
Smoking?
Wait, bulk smoke?
Are you saying I can throw a whole stack down, like, physically?
Right in front of it!
And he's like, like...
Now it's smoked.
That's great!
Bulk blasting!
And so anyway, I started bulk blasting.
Stripped mangrove wood...
Okay, so wood becomes charcoal...
I mean, that makes sense, I guess.
The salt becomes smooth.
Wait, I had no idea I could blast...
Hold on a minute.
You're shitting me?
Is this a vanilla thing?
Did I just...
Oops, hold on, I did something.
What happened?
What did I just put in here?
Oh, whatever.
Uh, I...
What did I just say?
I got distracted!
Fuck!
Uh...
Magma blocks?
I don't know what the fuck I was just doing.
I have no idea on earth what I was doing.
What I was just doing.
Make a noise!
Okay.
I feel like I'm cursed now.
Yeah, I...
I guess that's gone from my memory.
I have no idea what I was just doing.
Oh yeah, right, right!
Hamlet!
We're gonna play Hamlet.
Blaster!
Can I actually blast this?
What the fuck?
I don't remember being able to do that.
But, uh...
Okay.
Sounds good, man.
Cool!
What else?
There was more.
We...
Uh...
Actually, yeah.
I was looking at this.
Uh...
Give me this.
Washing.
Smoking.
Blasting.
Ow!
I heard you!
Oh!
They are coming for me.
What's my shield?
My shield is gone.
Put it on.
Tactical equipping.
Voluntary exile.
What's up, dudes?
What's going on?
Oh, god.
I think this guy has the enchantment that shoots through my shield.
Assholes.
They wanted a piece of my base.
I said no.
Okay.
Where was I?
I was looking at things.
Clutch!
No.
I was looking at this stuff.
Bulk plastic.
Let me see.
Okay.
So you can do that.
And you get just one iron nugget out of it.
That's, like, so bad.
Why would I ever do that, you know?
Clay ball becomes brick.
Cracked nether bricks.
Oh!
Maybe a better way of, uh, just smelting.
Depends how fast it is, I guess.
You can turn that into glass.
Oh!
Soul sand becomes scoria.
Okay.
Bulk haunting.
Dude, not only do we haunt things here, we do it in bulk.
That's how evil we are.
You haunt a brick, it becomes a nether brick.
That kind of makes sense.
A brown mushroom becomes a warped fungus.
Hey, that totally makes sense, all of this, actually.
Oh, so any kind of dirt becomes evil dirt.
Alright.
Ink sack, glowing sack, lapis lazuli becomes prismarine!
Fuck yeah!
I don't even need to go to the ocean.
Dude, I can do that right now.
But wait, I need to set up the whole thing.
Hold on.
I have a fan.
So that means I blacked out just now.
Hold on.
Wait, how am I gonna...
How do I do this?
I mean, I guess I can try a soul campfire, but I don't think that's gonna...
This looks like I'm setting it on fire.
Oh, wait!
Maybe you can only do this in the nether!
Oh!
I see!
That makes so much sense!
Yeah.
Sand becomes salt.
That makes so much sense, too.
Infested stone!
Huh?
That makes sense.
Okay, okay, cool!
I like it!
Mixing!
We got pulp!
Wait, is that better than...
Wait, do I have zinc?
Iron?
Rooted dirt becomes mud.
Okay, okay.
Compacting...
Sawing...
One andesite alloy becomes six shafts.
Shaft!
Right.
Yo, this looks so good!
Dude!
Holy sh... I want that!
Wait a minute, I can do this.
Hello?
Wait a sec.
Cut it!
Ladder?
Anticide ladder.
Oh, that's a slow one!
Look at that one!
Recipe filter.
Oh, okay, so if I only want... What did I just get?
Did I get shaft?
I think I got shaft.
What is that?
Anticide scaffolding.
Dude, actually sick looking.
I like me likey.
What did I just get?
Oh, anticide bars.
Huh.
That was kind of cool.
I can dig it.
You know, I'm a big fan of anticide now.
I do like it.
Oh!
Oh, here we go.
Anticide... Wait.
I can ponder the table?
I can use this to eat at...
Tablecloths can be used to display items.
Oh, nice.
Got it.
Excuse me?
With the help of a logistics system, they can also be used to sell items.
What do you mean?
What... what are you talking about?
Start with the shop's inventory, a packager, and stock link.
Sure.
I know some of those words.
Bind a stock ticker to the link and place it in the shop.
Buy my, uh... buy my Oliver coin.
Employ a mob or blaze burner as the shop... keeper?
What the...
Wait.
Are you saying that I can have villagers come by?
And they're gonna give me money?
Fill the shop inventory with items to be sold.
Huh?
To create a new trade, interact with the shopkeeper while holding a tablecloth.
Uh-huh.
You're kind of losing me.
Once placed, set a price in the item slot on the side.
On the side or on the side?
Or both?
Other players can now interact with the shop.
Oh, it's a multiplayer thing.
Oh, that explains so much.
I have so many questions.
When checking out at the cashier, the bought items will be placed into a package.
Why is this so complicated?
Why not just go, give money, I give bucks.
From there, they can be transported to the shop front.
I want belt, man!
I want belts, and I want suspenders.
Give it to me!
No, I know how to get it.
We need Gloop.
Green Gloop.
The payments will be stored inside the stock ticker book.
Whatever you say, bruh.
I am going on an expedition back to where we started to get some Gloop.
But first, let's just deposit all the stuff we have.
Uh, oh my god.
We need...
Okay, this is now also not just exotic stuff.
It's also, uh, create stuff.
I redelegate.
Let me actually see this.
What?!
Wait a minute.
Honestly, that looks kinda cool though.
Oh!
Yo!
Hold on.
This is sick looking.
Wait, I can take any block you're seeing?
Are you saying I can...
Calcite!
Table!
Uh, here.
Shit.
Hey!
Oh my god, it's Isa following me.
Oh no!
Oh shit!
I don't like that.
Get rid of it.
Boo.
No, it took the tablecloth away.
Or cover.
It's a double table.
This actually looks so good!
I have to spray my nuggets.
Can I have more than...
Looks like a bunch of light bulbs, doesn't it?
This house is weird so far.
I understand.
It's...
It's weird.
It will be better.
You'll see.
I have great plans for this.
Involving rotating doors and elevators and all kinds of stuff.
I just gotta get the flooring done.
Okay?
It's coming.
I feel like I'm close to a breakthrough on that.
Also, I never made this.
Let's make a brass casing.
I need the stripped variety.
Strip me up before I go, go.
Where's my brass?
And...
You ready?
Here we go.
The brass age.
Or the brassage.
Ha!
Hello!
What on earth is this?
I saw some exciting stuff just now.
Throttle lever.
Whoa.
List filter.
Yes.
Wait, what?
Okay, so wait.
What's the difference?
Hey!
A list filter becomes a list filter!
That's nuts.
No way.
Propeller bearing.
Dynamic?
We cannot get distracted.
No.
More.
Distractions.
Ominous banner.
No, that's exotic.
Shafts.
Let's actually cook some of this stuff that hasn't been cooked yet.
Blast it.
Man, I'm seriously lacking some fuel here.
Let's use some...
Uh, you know what?
Wait.
I have an idea.
Can I do that in here?
No, it's only this one.
Okay.
We are gonna make...
What?
Okay, watch!
Huh?
It feeds itself.
Look at this.
But of course, we can also use the new method.
Wait a minute.
Brass door.
No.
I don't like that one.
Uh, hold on.
Blasting.
No.
Wait, which one was it?
Okay, hold on.
Let's actually try this real quick.
We have lava, right?
We're gonna do this.
I can make it.
Um...
One last experiment before we go.
I promise it's the last.
What the hell is my...
There it is.
And then I need my bucket.
But hold on a minute.
How are we gonna prevent the lava from going zzzz everywhere?
This is an interesting...
Problem.
Hmm.
Wait a minute.
Do we even need lava for this?
Was it lava?
It is lava.
Yep.
That is...
That's lava.
Yep.
Let's just try.
Shall...
Oh!
I know.
I know what to do.
How about...
Watch.
Some good old...
Rating!
Huh?
Hopefully this won't, uh...
Melt.
Let me see.
Copper...
Here.
Oh, I need four of them some...
Wait, hold on.
That can't be right.
How about I get four out?
This is horribly inefficient.
I don't like what I'm doing.
It's okay though.
Where do we do it?
Let's try it right...
Up here near the other experiments.
Fan.
Oh wait!
Uh...
We probably need some...
Rotational...
Aha!
Okay.
So...
Where do we have that?
Here.
Or here.
Maybe we use...
Actually, you know what?
Uh...
Fuck this one.
This is being repurposed.
Mmm...
Yep.
That's good.
Now I need another wheel.
Just one wheel.
Like that.
Wind maker.
That's right.
I am the wind maker.
Let's make sure nothing...
Ah!
Fuck.
Stop it!
Lava!
No wait.
Here.
Lava!
Yeah!
You ready for this one?
Is it being blasted?
What?
Processing by particle.
I
couldn't jump out of there!
What the hell, man?
Okay.
Clearly that's some bullshit.
Wait.
Did
my fucking items disappear?
There's no way!
Oh my god.
What did I lose?
Oh fuck!
Yeah, we're not doing that.
That's a hell no from me.
Not until we have a better solution in place.
This, this, this.
Nope.
Absolutely not.
We need a system in place before we do any of this.
Shit.
Dude, I lost, like...
So much.
Just now.
I think.
I don't even know what I lost.
It was so extensive.
The loss, that is.
The loss was so extensive.
Man.
Give me dirt.
Fuck this, I'm going on an expedition.
But you know what this means, right?
You know what this means.
This means I can definitely murder my cows.
And I will.
I will.
I'm gonna set up an automated slaughter contraption.
They're gonna be on fire.
They will feel what I felt.
And boy, I did not feel good.
Okay?
They shall feel it.
Now, I lost everything.
I lost my shovel, too.
Do we even have any diamonds, bro?
What is going on right now?
I've...
I've got nothing.
You know what, uh...
No.
I'm gonna half rage quit out of that one.
We'll fix it in post.
Meaning next time.
Man.
Let's put on some sad music.
What is sad?
This one is sad.
Hey, Jackie's here right on cue.
What's up?
You know what happened, Jackie?
I fell into a lava fan.
And I lost it all.
I know.
I can't believe it happened.
What's up, guys?
She's in my arms.
She's supporting me.
She knew I went through something bad.
Oh, now she jumped off.
Okay.
That was the emotional support I got.
No more.
At least you didn't lose your pickaxe.
You're right, I didn't.
That's actually...
Thank you.
Silver lining.
You're right.
That's how you should look at it.
I don't know what I...
I maybe expected to be set on fire down there, but I didn't expect to immediately die.
Because I went from 100 to zero in no time.
You know, I was sort of ready.
Okay, maybe I'll catch fire.
I'll jump out, you know?
But I couldn't even jump out for some reason.
I learned my lesson, though.
Dude, I got blasted.
It's lavaed air.
That's a good way to put it.
In hindsight, it wasn't a smart idea to jump into the blaster.
Just give it the name, you know?
You don't want to do that.
I was like, how am I gonna get my item otherwise?
But there's gotta be a way to extract that item, I imagine.
A hopper, for example.
There's many ways to do that.
Worth a test?
I think so, yeah.
I learned my lesson.
I will never attempt that again.
By the way, the last S in chassis is silent for whatever reason.
Okay, so chassis...
Chassis?
Is that how you say it?
Chassis.
It's not chassis, right?
It's chassis.
Okay, good.
The CH is also pronounced...
Oh, chassis.
Really?
Chassis.
Ah!
Okay, thank you.
Learning English.
I got it, I got it.
I will never forget it now.
It's like, I keep saying miscellaneous when it's really miscellaneous.
Must be my...
German I learned once in a while.
They always go shh on things, you know, so that's ingrained in me.
Miscellaneous.
Actually, now that I say it like that, it does sound very smooth.
You know, miscellaneous.
It's so much easier to say, too.
So how would you pronounce it if it's like shortened?
Just mis?
Because I always think misc.
But that is totally...
Yeah, right, misc!
That's what I do.
Misk.
But that doesn't even sound right.
Oliver, you're a Danish legend.
Are you?
I think.
English makes no sense even to native speakers.
I think English makes a lot of sense.
It's one of the few languages that makes sense.
In a lot of ways.
But I see what you're talking about.
I see what you mean.
I'm at the gym watching your stream between sets.
How?
How are you doing that?
On your phone or something?
With headphones in or...
What is your setup like?
Frigidero.
I've never been inside a gym in my life.
It's like this mythical place in my mind.
I don't even know what it's like.
Never stepped foot inside a gym.
Not gym.
I guess there's no way to pronounce it differently.
Same here.
I'm at the gym as well.
What?
Why are you guys at the gym?
Watching me at the gym.
That's kind of weird.
Isn't it?
Just my phone and AirPods?
Oh, okay.
I guess that's a dumb question on my part.
What else would you do?
It's not like you bring a laptop to the gym.
Obviously it would be the phone.
And I hope I'm not on speaker.
You know, that would be even weirder.
You're a source of motivation to pull more reps?
Really?
Well, I'm glad to be of assistance.
May you get ripped.
I wish you all the best.
I'm not falling for that bait.
Kedawik.
Or Kerawik.
I do like Gears.
I love the Gears.
Vintage Story?
That game is not finished though, right?
It's still in development.
Are you gonna release the custom JEI mod?
There's actually no JEI in it anymore.
The JEI is completely stripped of it.
The animations you see and stuff, it's not actually JEI.
It is native create.
JEI is just the surface that is using to display it.
Yeah.
Maybe at some point.
People just don't like how the sausage is made, you know?
So I kinda just wanna keep it to myself.
For now.
I think.
There's like over a hundred unit tests in that mod so far.
To check that whenever a change is made, nothing gets broken.
It is actually incredibly solid right now.
Like, I've been running fucking...
Simulations of players running through it.
You know, over 400.
Just testing shit.
So I don't have to get spoiled.
It's kinda nuts.
I've been going a little too hard on that.
This dream was so overwhelming.
At times I can see why.
I was also overwhelmed.
We can be overwhelmed together.
Could you say a Danish tongue twister?
It would be very funny.
Uh...
That's a good one.
Very common one.
Or you can say...
Which is like a very long word in Danish.
Nobody uses that word.
But it is a thing.
Or you can say...
Oh, I got them all.
I had that on command.
What?
Exactly.
You got it.
What does the word mean?
I...
It's apparently a job.
Or was a job.
Imagine having that job and being asked what you do for a job.
I would hate being asked that question.
You're just making sounds, right?
I mean, isn't that what language is?
Those are actual words.
The Danish people in chat will confirm.
I work with people.
Exactly.
That's a good answer.
It sounds so normal to hear you talk Danish.
It's like you're just a regular guy.
Well, I am a regular guy.
I am so regular, you don't even understand.
I'm extremely regular.
Who are you most excited to incinerate, Oliver?
Uh...
Maybe the pigs.
Get some bacon.
No, but definitely like monsters, right?
Imagine the...
The Orphan Crusher just...
Ramped up to 11.
Of course, there are certain things I need to think about regarding the mob spawning on that one, but...
I'll think of something.
Yeah, the Orphan Crusher.
It's gonna be the Orphan Incinerator.
Exactly!
Hey, I thought the same thing at the same time.
That's funny.
Like, right when you wrote it.
Orphan Blaster!
That's even better!
You guys are amazing.
You come up with the funniest shit, man.
I forgot who it was who came up with Orphan Crusher, but that is just...
What a fantastic...
Word, you know?
Or description for it.
It's beautiful.
You guys are so fucking good.
Orphan Blaster!
Oh man!
We're gonna blast these orphans!
That sounds terrible!
Man!
Who was that actually?
It was Idle Villager?
Was it?
Sounds right!
Incinerate the creeper.
Yeah, I would love to do that.
Give them some of their own medicine.
You know?
We're bulk blasting the orphans!
We're not just killing them...
Dude, this is getting a little...
I don't know.
A little concentrated...
Concent...
Concentration camp-ish.
The stuff we're talking about here.
It's not good.
Hahaha!
That's fucked up, man.
I mean, the monsters though.
They are evil.
They need to die.
Wait, nevermind, you're right.
Hahaha!
Talking about orphans like Technoblade.
Isn't that a Minecrafter?
I feel like you guys have told me about that before.
Like a famous Minecraft person.
Player.
Oh!
I think you guys told me about this.
He died.
Yeah.
That's so sad.
How did he die anyway?
Like...
What happened?
Was he like sick or something?
Aw, fuck!
Cancer, man.
Dude, so many of my friends...
Parents and relatives have cancer.
It's just a menace.
It's always cancer, isn't it?
Man.
I've never been a fan of cancer, sorry, but that was just kind of funny.
I mean, yeah.
Honestly, the only time cancer is good is when you're playing...
The Binding of Isaac.
That is the only time.
Then I welcome it.
Jackie's trying to jump up on me.
She knows it's about the end of the stream, so she's getting ready to play.
It's always so annoying, actually, because right when the stream ends, it's usually when I want to eat.
You know, so what I end up doing is that I make the food, and then in between, like, you know, stirring the food, I will play with her, you know?
But she's like, immediately when the stream is over, we need to play now.
I'm like, no, I gotta eat as well.
Cat hair in the food.
Nah, you gotta be careful with that.
I love how you play mods exactly like I do.
As a hobo in a forest, with a bunch of chests under trees and a half-finished house.
But the thing is, it's not by choice, Rodonese.
I think you agree with me, we're probably the same.
Like, we want to make a nice house, but we kinda wanna get ready for the house, so we can make the house really nice, and not just build it from the start, right?
We wanna make a pre-staging area before the big thing.
This is definitely just temporary.
You know what I mean.
Build a house and sleep outside.
I mean, if you think about it, if I sleep inside the house right now, it's still outside.
There's no roof.
It doesn't make a difference.
When will you move into the house?
I can probably say with confidence, in the next stream.
In the next stream, I am moving in and there will be...
maybe a roof.
But I will move in.
Next stream, the day after tomorrow.
Or tomorrow.
Most likely the day after tomorrow.
Wait, today's Wednesday, right?
Friday would be a nice day to stream.
I've been slacking on XCOM lately.
I need to... I need to play a lot of that.
I've been obsessed with the Minecraft stuff and, you know, creating that mod and stuff.
Can't stop prompting!
You know, like, I've totally just...
left XCOM in the dust a little bit.
I need to get back into it.
In fact, I'll probably play some of that tonight.
And maybe upload it this evening if I... if I can manage to do it in time.
Are you still planning on making an elevator in the cave?
Yes, definitely!
That's, like, one of the big things I'm so excited about.
Especially now that I saw the ponder about it.
And the ponder stole my idea!
For the look of it.
Not that it's a very...
great idea.
I mean, it's pretty obvious, I guess.
That you would make it that way.
But, yeah, you know.
Definitely.
The factory must grow.
Yeah, when I get my belts!
As soon as I get my belts, then it's gonna grow.
And I already have a plan about that.
I'm gonna have an actual factory building.
With, like, andesite girders and, you know, industrial-looking piping and shit.
It's going to look nasty.
And I will have a pipe that completely messes up the ocean.
I will pollute.
Is what I'm saying.
Pollution is coming.
To the land.
This once green land shall become a wasteland.
Under my industrialism.
Engraved!
Exactly that!
That's what I had in mind, actually.
You read my mind.
Someday you'll get the belts and it'll be glorious to see.
I know!
It'll happen.
In fact, it'll happen next time.
You heard it here first.
I was actually gonna put Stuart in the mixer.
Because I have a theory that if I mix him up, he could potentially become the stuff for night or, like, invisibility potion.
That's the other ingredient.
I will mix him up into a little potion.
And then I will drink him.
I wonder if you could do that.
Like, you probably can't take damage from it.
I'm not sure, actually.
Maybe.
Be a brutalist, make a house out of stone and cardboard.
I don't like cardboard, though.
It should just be a stone hut with no windows.
It's just a frickin'... like the diorite cube.
You know?
On the... on the server.
Cool music.
I know, right?
It's from Persona.
Persona 5 has incredible music.
So many banger tracks in that game.
Guys, I'm outta here.
I'm going to go play with Jackie and make some food.
Thank you for watching.
And I will see you in the next stream.
Have a wonderful evening.
Bye-bye.